[ Background Sounds ]
[ Applause ]
>> Hi everyone.
My -- welcome to our session on
"What's New in iTunes Connect?"
My name is Daniel Meoh.
I'm an engineering manager on
iTunes Connect.
So we're going to talk about a
number of new features today.
Some of these we launched
earlier this year and the rest
will be rolling out over the
course of the rest of this year.
We're going to talk about
everything from responding to
customer reviews to new ways to
control how your app versions
arrive in your customers' hands.
So let's jump right in and start
by talking about ratings,
reviews, and responses.
Now since we did launch this a
few months ago, how many of you
have already used this feature?
[ Scattered Applause ]
Great. Well, whether you've used
this or not, I'm sure we can all
agree that directly engaging our
customers benefits everybody.
So before we talk about how to
respond let's take a minute to
think about why customers write
reviews in the first place.
So sometimes our customers just
love our apps and they want to
let the world know.
Other times customers may be a
little confused as to why maybe
you've included or not included
certain features or maybe around
design decisions you may have
made.
And finally, we're all familiar
with this, customers often take
to reviews to let us know about
bugs or crashes in our apps.
Now no matter what the reason
is, why customers write these
reviews, we have a great way for
you to respond.
Now here we see iTunes Connect.
This is where you've always come
to read reviews from your
customers and now this is where
you come to respond.
We're going to take a look at
our app, Forest Xplorer, which
is a fictitious app for a hiking
and trail navigation.
So let's look for a review to
respond to.
We're going to start by looking
for two-star reviews that don't
yet have any developer
responses.
And here we have one that we can
take a look at.
It looks like we have a customer
that's been using our app for a
long time and just recently she
went hiking and found that one
of the app -- one of the trails
that she was on was outdated.
Well, it turns out we released a
new version of our app just this
morning and it refreshes the
trails in her area.
So let's go ahead and let her
know that.
We'll start the process by
clicking the "reply" button next
to her review, which brings up
this modal where we can type in
our response.
Here we'll let her know that we
really appreciate her using our
app for so long and that she
should check out the new version
we released this morning because
it should address her concerns.
Once we hit "submit" this
response shows up right under
the review.
Now you may notice that the word
"pending" appears next to the
response title.
All this means is that this
response has not yet made it to
the system to show up on the App
Store.
Once it does this word "pending"
will disappear.
For those of you who are
wondering, this has nothing to
do with app review.
Now one other thing to note here
is that every review only has
one response.
So your customer can update the
review as much as they like and
you can update your response as
often as you'd like, but this is
not a threaded conversation.
So it will only be one pairing
per customer.
Now once this response does make
it all the way to the store your
customer will receive a
notification.
This comes in the form of both a
push and an email notification.
This notification is triggered
when you, as a developer, submit
your initial response or update
an existing one after a customer
has updated their review.
Any other times you update your
response will not trigger a
notification.
On your end you can also opt
into an email notification.
This will be triggered when a
customer updates the review
after you've responded.
You can enable this by going
into the "use/enroll" section of
iTunes Connect.
All right, going back to our
scenario; here our customer has
tapped the "update review" link
in the email notification that
she received.
This gives her the chance to
obviously update her review.
It takes her directly into the
App Store to her review.
So it turns out our customer has
updated her app and it worked
out really well for her.
So she's decided to update her
review to five stars.
Once she hits the "send" button
we have another satisfied
customer.
Now looking at some early stats
around this feature, we notice
that all of the reviews that
were updated after developer
response, it was an average of
about a one and a half star
increase to these reviews.
So that sounds like a great
reason to go out there and start
engaging your customers.
We also have a number of best
practices around this feature.
First, customers of course like
to know that they're being
listened to.
So stay on top of what they're
saying and respond in a timely
manner.
One way you can do this is to
opt into those notifications
that we were talking about
earlier.
That way when customers update
their reviews after your
response you can get a good
feeling of how they 're reacting
to your responses.
Next, really listen to your
customers before you respond,
and when you do respond, respond
specifically to the thing
they're talking to you about.
Try to stay positive and please
don't use this to advertise or
to incentivize higher ratings.
If you are responding or
releasing a new version that
addresses concerns that
customers have been talking
about, like features or bug
reports, be sure to include this
in your "what's new" text with
your version update.
This way as many customers as
possible will know that you've
addressed their concerns.
You can also take this
opportunity to respond to those
customers so they can be
notified that a new version is
available to take a look at.
And finally, if you do have
sensitive customer information
please be mindful of the fact
that this is a public forum so
treat it that way.
We have a new store kit API
around this feature that allows
you to collect both reviews and
ratings from directly inside of
your apps without sending your
customers to the App Store.
So be sure to come to our
"What's New in Store Kit"
session tomorrow at 11 to find
out more about that.
All right, now let's talk about
test flight.
So test flight is our beta
testing platform.
It allows you to distribute your
prerelease app builds to testers
to vet your builds before you
distribute them to the App Store
at large.
Now we made a number of
enhancements to this platform
recently, both around how you
distribute builds and how you
manage testers.
So I'd like to invite Tom Neglen
up to the stage to talk to us
about this.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, Daniel.
I'm really excited to talk about
Test Flight.
In April, we introduced multiple
build support.
You're now able to distribute
more than one build to your
external testers at the same
time.
You can do this by organizing
your testers into groups and
assigning one or more builds to
each group.
Your internal iTunes Connect
testers will now get access to
all Test Flight builds.
So when you upload a new build
it's automatically made
available to your internal
testers.
We've also added individual
tester metrics so you can see
who is actively testing and who
is experiencing crashes.
Last, but not least, we added a
"tester reinvite" button.
It's really easy to go into
iTunes Connect and send a new
invite to a specific tester with
one click.
Now I'd like to show you what's
possible with these new
features.
Let's start with the simple
example of using a group to send
a build to your testers.
We can create a group by
clicking "new group" in the left
nav and giving our group a name.
We'll call this group "Beta
Testers."
Let's say we want to use this
group to test major feature
changes.
We might want to add our QA team
or other individuals who don't
mind finding an occasional bug.
We can add testers to the group
by clicking the plus button next
to "testers" and selecting "add
new testers."
All that's required to invite a
tester to our app is an email
address and the name is
optional.
So we've added some testers to
the group, but they won't
actually receive an invite to
test the app until we've also
added at least one build to the
group.
And we can do that in the
"build" sub tab by clicking the
plus button.
We're given a dialogue where we
can browse all of our builds and
when we select a build we're
given an opportunity to update
the test information before that
build goes out to testers.
So we could add some notes here
to let testers know what to look
for as they're testing this
build and if we've added a new
feature or made some changes to
an area of an app we might want
to mention that here.
And with that, the build has
been added to the group and will
be delivered to our beta
testers.
So let's take a look at what
testers will see.
Once they've been given access
to a build they receive an
invite to test the app.
We only send the invite once and
testers won't have access to any
builds until they accept the
invite.
So here's what the invitation
looks like and when testers tap
"view in test flight" it'll
launch the test flight app.
Here, testers will be able to
accept the invitation and
install the beta app.
They'll also be able to see the
notes we added on what to test
and they can provide feedback by
tapping "send feedback."
Now let's say our testers have
used our build for a while and
they've given us feedback about
a bug they've found.
We could use the feedback to fix
the bug and upload a new build.
We'll want to add the build to
our beta testers group and when
we're prompted we'll want to
update the test information to
let testers know that the bug
has been fixed.
Once the build is added to the
group, it'll be delivered to our
beta testers so they could
install and verify the fix.
So that's a simple way to use a
group to send builds to your
testers.
But aside from just finding bugs
in your app, you might also want
to use groups as a way to
collect feedback, maybe from
some of your power users who
like giving feedback on early
iterations or maybe from your
CEO or potential investors.
You likely don't want to give
them the same builds that you
give your beta testers.
You want to ensure that you've
worked out all the issues before
you send them a build.
We can easily do this by
creating an additional group.
Again, we'll click "new group"
in the left nav and give our
group a name.
We'll call this group
"stakeholders."
We'll add some of our power
users to this group and then
when we're ready, we'll take a
build that's been thoroughly
vetted by our beta testers and
add it to the stakeholders'
group.
The stable build will be
delivered to our stakeholders so
they could begin to provide
feedback.
That shows how you can use the
flexibility of groups to give
different builds to different
sets of testers.
Taking this concept further, we
can even create three different
groups and give them names like
"alpha," "beta," and maybe
"release candidate."
You could push frequent builds
to your "alpha" group and insure
that any issues are isolated to
the testers in that group.
As your build becomes more
stable, you could promote it to
the larger "beta" group.
And once you've reached the
level of confidence with the
stability of your build, you
could go onto promote it to the
"release candidate" group.
Even if you've fixed all bugs at
this point, you could still use
the testers in your "release
candidate" group to collect
further feedback before
releasing a final version to the
App Store.
Another option would be to use
groups for two separate lines of
development.
For example we can create an
additional group that we use
solely for experimental
features.
And we can ensure that the
builds we add to this group are
isolated from our standard
releases and we can control
exactly which testers get access
to these builds.
So I showed a couple ways to use
groups for build distribution
and I'm sure you'll come up with
more.
Another example that I want to
show is a way to organize
testers before you even have a
build that's ready for them.
It might be nice to create a new
group called "WWDC."
You could add contacts that you
meet at the conference who might
later like to try a prereleased
version of your app.
They won't actually receive an
invite until you have a build
that's ready for them and you
add it to the group.
There's also a special default
group called "iTunes Connect
Users" and this is considered
your internal group.
Well, what does that mean?
Only members of your iTunes
Connect Team can be added as
testers to this group.
And unlike other groups, members
in your internal group will get
access to all test flight
builds.
So you might want to use this
for your development team or
those close to the development
cycle.
We've looked at a few different
ways to organize testers and
give them access to different
builds.
Let's take a look at how testers
can interact with the builds
that they have access to.
Once they've been given access
to a build -- I'm sorry -- in
the test flight app we always
show testers the latest build
that's available to them.
Here they can see previous
builds, but only ones that they
have access to.
They'll be able to see the notes
on what to test and they can
easily switch between versions
by tapping "install."
It's really nice to be able to
switch between different beta
versions at any time.
Our QA team really likes this.
So let's take a look at tester
management.
Back in iTunes Connect under
"all testers", we can see who
has accepted the invite.
We could sort by status to find
testers who have yet to accept
and if we want, we can send them
a new invite by clicking "resend
invite."
We also have a session count and
this will tell us how many times
each tester has used our app.
If we want to remove a tester,
we can easily do that by
clicking "edit" and selecting
the testers we'd like to remove.
Then we simply click "remove."
Now, if you remove a tester from
the "all testers" section, this
would remove that tester from
your app.
They'd be removed from all
groups and would no longer have
access to builds.
You could, of course, simply
remove a tester from a specific
group and this would just remove
their access to the builds in
that group.
Another metric that we have is
the crash count and this will
show us which testers are
experiencing problems.
And if they haven't provided
feedback already it might be a
good idea to reach out.
These metrics are also available
when looking at a group and the
numbers that you see will only
correlate to the builds in that
group.
So when you make builds
available to testers they'll be
installable up until they
expire.
When do builds expire?
Builds will automatically expire
90 days after they're uploaded.
You could remove a build from
distribution earlier by going to
the "build detail" page and
clicking "expire build."
This would prevent future
installs, but testers who have
already installed will still be
able to launch the app until the
original 90-day interval is
reached.
Also keep in mind you're
currently limited to 2000
external testers.
Later this year we're going to
be increasing that number and
we'll be increasing it to
10,000.
[ Applause ]
We're really excited about this.
So those are just a few tips to
mention when using Test Flight
to distribute prereleased
versions of your app.
You can find many more in the
"Developer Guide" and you'll
also find a link to the Test
Flight Release Notes, where you
can stay informed on new
features and future STK support.
With that I'll give the stage
back to Daniel.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, Tommy.
So those are some great new
features we've added to Test
Flight including the ability to
distribute multiple builds to
testers at the same time, group
testers and distribute builds to
those groups, and of course the
increase from 2000 to 10,000
testers.
All right, now let's move on to
talking about the new App Store.
Now you've been hearing about
this all week.
We've gone back and we've
redesigned the App Store from
scratch.
And we've done this not just to
make it easier for customers to
discover new apps, but also to
surface the rich culture around
our app ecosystem that exists
even today.
It all begins on the "today"
tab.
This tab is a daily destination
that contains a collection of
apps that are curated by our
editorial team into stories.
These stories tell customers not
just what apps they love, but
why they would love them.
By clicking or tapping on any of
the icons on the "today" tab or
anywhere else around the App
Store you see the product page.
The product page is the home for
one of our apps.
Now the changes that have
happened around iTunes Connect
that effect the new App Store
mostly surface on this page.
So let's take a look at some of
these changes.
First we'll take a look at the
app icon.
Beginning with iOS 11 and Xcode
9, you'll no longer be managing
your app icon in iTunes Connect.
Instead you'll be including your
icon in the asset catalogue of
your app binary.
[ Applause ]
Along with this change you'll be
able to deliver wide gamut
images for your icons that will
be displayed in full fidelity on
all supported devices.
And if you're working with
multiple color spaces you can
take advantage of Xcode's color
management features to make sure
your icons display accurately on
all your target devices.
And thanks to app thinning you
won't have to worry about the
binary being delivered to your
customer being unnecessarily
large just because you've
included an icon.
Next, let's talk about the
subtitle field.
The subtitle is a new field
that's meant to be a brief
summary of your app's experience
in a concise and compelling way.
This field is up to 30
characters in length and it's
meant to compliment your app
name.
This means whenever your app
name shows up around the store
your subtitle shows up along
with it.
This could be the product page
or the search page or any of the
new tabs.
Now many of you already include
this information today with your
apps.
Your app name may look like
this.
Well, with the new subtitle
field you can move this
information out of your app name
and really highlight your brand
and let your app names
standalone without sacrificing
searchability or the context
that the subtitle brings.
As we move further down on the
product page, we get to app
previews.
With the new App Store you can
submit up to three app previews
and that's three previews per
language.
As your customers browse the
store, your previews will
automatically play bringing your
apps to life and immediately
engaging your customers.
Below app previews, we see the
description and prepended to
this description is a
promotional text field.
In iTunes Connect, you'll find
this new field that's always
editable and is meant to contain
frequently changing information.
Today, you might let people know
that your app is free for a
limited time or maybe 40 percent
off for a holiday weekend.
Well, in the future, your
description will be locked after
app review, so please use this
field for this kind of
information.
And we have one more exciting
feature that we'd like to talk
about that allows to surface
your in-app purchases directly
on the App Store and let your
customers interact with those in
app purchases right away.
I'd like to invite Will Avrell
up to the stage to tell you more
about it.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, Daniel.
We're extremely pleased to
announce that for the first time
we're making in app purchases
discoverable on the App Store.
[applause] Yeah!
[applause] Give it up!
[applause] In addition,
customers will be able to start
their in app purchase right on
the App Store and be taken
directly to your app to complete
the purchase.
Overall, we feel like this is a
terrific way for developers to
gain additional exposure for
their in-app purchases on the
App Store.
So with that said, let's take a
dive in and look at where
promoted in-app purchases will
be discoverable on the new App
Store.
So the first place that Daniel
talked about is the product
page.
As you scroll down the product
page, you'll find your promoted
in app purchases broken up in
two -- into two distinct lists;
your subscriptions and all
in-app purchase -- all other
in-app purchase types.
It's important to note here that
you are limited to 20 in app
purchases per app.
Also unique to the product page
view is the ability to customize
the order and visibility of your
promoted in-app purchases as
they appear on your product
page.
This means you can do things
like hide subscriptions the user
already has purchased on the
device or if you have a puzzle
game, you can show the most
relevant levels earlier in the
list.
So for example, if the customer
just beat level two in your game
-- your puzzle game -- you can
make sure that level three is
the first thing that they see in
this list.
So moving on, promoted in app
purchases are now searchable on
the App Store.
This means you can go to this
search tab and you can search by
the name or description of your
promoted in-app purchase and see
some results.
Also we're adding a new
"trending" section for promoted
in-app purchase searches,
similar to what exists today for
apps.
And finally, promoted in-app
purchases are eligible to be
featured by the App Store
editorial team.
This means that your app could
be featured on the "today" apps
or games tab.
In this section, you get a nice
little write up about your
promoted in app purchase and
tapping anything but the "buy"
button here will forward you to
the product page whereas
clicking on the "buy" button
will open the app and complete
the purchase.
So, I've talked a lot about what
promoted in-app purchases are
and where they appear on the new
App Store, but let's discuss
what you as a developer need to
do to implement and make an
in-app purchase a promoted
in-app purchase.
So we've broken this down into
three steps, the first two of
which are managed in iTunes
Connect, but critically you must
define some promotional data for
your promoted in-app purchase.
This is an image, a name, and a
description.
So these are the three pieces of
information that are surfaced
and visible on the App Store and
because that's the case, they
must be reviewed by the app
review team.
Also, you might be familiar with
name and description, as these
are fields that exist today in
iTunes Connect, but we've
adjusted the limits slightly and
the new character limits are 30
and 45 respectively.
So once you've set up your
promotional data in iTunes
Connect you need to configure
your in app purchase and you
need to do things like activate
it so we know to count it
against your limit of 20 and you
need to set a default order and
visibility for your promoted
in-app purchase as it would
appear on the product page.
Lastly, you need to implement
some store kit APIs, well just
one, but it is absolutely
critical that you implement a
single delegate method on the SK
Payment Transaction Observer
Protocol.
If you do not implement this
single delegate method, your
promoted in app purchases will
not appear on the App Store.
So I mentioned the ability to
customize the order and
visibility of your promoted
in-app purchases as they appear
on the product page and that is
accomplished through the SK
Products Store Promotion
Controller API.
So again, like I said, using
this API, you can show more
relevant promoted in app
purchases on your product page.
I won't go into too much detail
about how to implement this in
code or the impressive array of
options you can do with this
optional store kit API, but be
sure to check out the "What's
New in Store Kits" session,
which is tomorrow at 11 a.m. to
figure out more about how to use
these APIs and how to implement
them.
So as I mentioned, the first two
portions of implementing a
promoted in-app purchase is done
in iTunes Connect and I'd like
to take this moment to demo for
you exactly what it will look
like to set up an in-app
purchase as a promoted in-app
purchase when this feature
launches later this summer.
So hopefully everyone's familiar
with this view, but all I've
done at this point is go to the
iTunes Connect website and log
in with my user name and
password.
So from here we're going to
click on the "my apps" module
and that'll take us to iTunes
Connect and our my apps page
where you get a nice little list
of all of our apps.
So we've been talking about
Forest Xplorer and, in fact, we
just launched a brand new
subscription called Pro
Subscription and we'd like to
make this promoted and visible
on the App Store.
So the first step here is to
click on the Forest Xplorer app.
This takes us into the app
information view where we see
some global information about
our app as a whole.
We can set our name, our
subtitle, change the category.
But this isn't really what we're
concerned with here so we're
going to click on the "features"
tab and clicking the "features"
tab automatically selects the
in-app purchase left nav here
and this takes us to all of our
in-app -- purchases for the
Forest Xplorer app.
Again, I'm really concerned with
the Pro Subscription so I'm
going to go ahead and click on
"Pro Subscription."
Doing so took me into the in-app
purchase detail view and as we
scroll down this page a lot of
this should be familiar to you
if you've used in app purchases
in iTunes Connect, but there's a
brand new section which is
called App Store Promotion and
this is how we begin setting up
our in app purchase to be a
promoted in-app purchase.
So the first thing we have to do
is upload an image.
So I'm going to go ahead and
click "choose file" and perfect,
my image is ready right here.
Let's just take a look.
Yeah, that looks good.
So we'll select this and
immediately you'll notice that
our image was masked and is now
shown right next to our name and
description.
So this gives us a nice little
preview of what our promoted
in-app purchase will look like
on the App Store.
Again, I'll just mention that
since these three pieces of data
are surfaced on the App Store
they must be reviewed, even
though our Pro Subscription in
app purchase is already approved
and ready for sale.
Additionally I'll talk to this
checkbox right here, which is
your default visibility.
So in our case we have no plans
to implement the optional store
kit API.
So it's best for us to leave
this checked because if we were
to uncheck this and not
implement the store kit API, we
would never override the
visibility of false and it would
never be displayed on the App
Store.
So I'm going to go ahead and
leave that checked.
Also, I noticed when I uploaded
my image, my name and
description field changed colors
and that's because we introduced
new limits for these fields.
So my old name and description
are longer than the allowable
limits.
So I'm going to go ahead and
edit these.
So I'm going to make this just
Pro Subscription.
And I'm going to remove the
duration from the description
here.
So that's great.
I'm now under the limits for
both of these fields and I can
go ahead and click "save."
So I've set up the promotional
data for this in-app purchase
and I'm almost there, but I do
need to configure it.
To configure this in-app
purchase and really make it a
promoted in app purchase I need
to go to the App Store
promotions navigation here on
the left and this takes me to a
list of all my in app purchases
that have promotional data
associated with them.
So you can see my Pro
Subscription was added to the
very top of this list, but it's
not yet active, which means it
will not be displayed on the App
Store.
So to activate my Pro
Subscription, I simply click on
the checkbox here and you'll
notice that clicking the
checkbox automatically gave it a
sort position of one.
So these orderings or sort
positions are manageable by
sliding each of these boxes.
So I'm going to move it down to
two.
I'll move it down to three.
And you can also click this
arrow, which will conveniently
take you to the very top of the
list automatically.
So as I mentioned, you are
limited to 20 active promoted
in-app purchases per app, but
you can have as many set up with
promotional data as you want.
So potentially this list could
get very long and to help manage
that, we have a filter right
here to the right.
So you can filter promoted and
not promoted in-app purchases.
So we like the way this looks.
We want our Pro Subscription
number one in the list so we're
going to go ahead and click
"save."
And that's how easy it is to set
up a promoted in app purchase in
iTunes Connect.
At this point I'd like to give
the stage back to Daniel.
Thank you for your time.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, Will.
So the ability to promote in app
purchases will be available for
all in app purchase types.
And whether you have an iOS or a
universal app you'll be able to
take advantage of this feature.
And, just like the rest of the
new App Store, this will be
available in iOS 11.
Now let's move on to phased
release.
Now imagine with me for a minute
that you're about to release a
great new version of your app to
the store.
You put it through an extended
period of beta testing and
you've subjected it to multiple
rounds of low testing.
The moment you release it to the
store, you watch your production
environment crumble.
Now we understand that
production is always a unique
environment, no matter how much
testing you've done.
And that's why we built Phase
Release.
So let's take a look at how this
works.
When you choose a version to be
enabled for Phase Release and
you push that version to this
App Store, that version is
available immediately, just like
any version is today.
So if a customer goes to the App
Store and does a manual update
or downloads that app for the
first time they will be
receiving this newest version.
Now the difference with Phase
Release is that users who
receive this version over
automatic updates will receive
it over a gradual seven-day
period.
So on day one up to one percent
of your customers who are
receiving this over automatic
updates will have this available
to them.
By day two you'll be up to two
percent.
By day four; 10 percent.
And when they get to day seven,
all of your customers who are
using automatic updates will
have this latest version
available.
Now remember, if any of these
customers do go directly to the
App Store to either update or to
download for the first time,
during this period they will
receive the latest version right
away.
So let's look at how we might
set this up in iTunes Connect.
So let's say we're about to
release a brand new version of
our Forest Xplorer app and we'd
like to use Phase Release.
In order to do this, before we
release this version, we can go
to the bottom of our version
page and choose "release over a
seven-day period."
Once we've done this and the
version is available on the
store this area changes and we
see a day counter instead.
Under each day is a maximum
number of customers who will
receive this over automatic
updates.
Now let's say on day three we
realize that we have some
concerns about production.
At this point, we'd like to
pause our phase release.
In order to do this, we simply
choose "pause phase release"
from the radio buttons in this
area and then this area turns
gray.
This means that no more of our
customers are receiving this
over automatic updates while
we're paused.
If customers go directly to the
store, they will continue being
able to pull the latest version.
Now eight days later, we've
addressed our performance issues
and we're ready to resume our
release.
So we simply, at this point,
choose "resume phase release"
and we're back in motion.
Now we come to day five and
we're confident that our
production environment is ready
to handle the full load.
So we'd like to release this to
all of our customers right away.
In order to do this, we choose
"release to all users" in the
top right corner of the page and
once we confirm this decision,
this version is now available to
all of our customers.
The phase release is available
to you today and no matter --
[ Applause ]
And no matter which version of
iOS your customers are using,
you can use this feature with
all of them.
And that's Phase Release.
So we'd like to close out our
session as we do every year,
with some tips from app review
about how to get your versions
through review a little more
smoothly.
So we'll start by talking about
making sure your app functions
throughout the review process.
Now a lot of us have external
services that our apps depend on
to function correctly.
So please make sure your
external services continue to
function, otherwise we can't
complete the review of your apps
that depend on them.
Next, please run your versions
on an actual device before you
submit.
Running on a simulator is not an
actual device.
Next, if there is any sign-in
information that your app
requires, please include this on
the version page.
We do get a lot of submissions
where the sign in information is
either missing or it's out of
date.
So when you do move from version
to version please make sure that
this information is current.
If there are any obscure parts
of your apps or just areas that
are difficult to get to, please
let us know in your app review
notes.
If there's anything else we
should know about your app,
please feel free to use your
field -- this field for that as
well.
And our binary compatibility
team may reach out to you over
resolution center if they have
any concerns about your binary
being compatible with say the
OS.
So don't be concerned if they do
happen to send you a message.
And finally, please use keywords
that are relevant for your apps
and keywords that you have the
rights to use.
[laughter] And those are some
notes from app review.
So in conclusion, we've talked
about many new features that
change the way you work with
your apps, from new ways to
distribute builds during beta
testing to new controls over how
you release your app versions to
your customers.
And once your apps are on the
store we've created a new way
for your customers to discover
your apps and when your
customers are ready to leave you
feedback you now have new
avenues to engage those
customers and respond to their
feedback.
For more information about what
we've talked about today and any
related information such as app
review, guideline updates, or
changes to sales and trends
around subscriptions, please
visit this link.
We also have a number of related
sessions.
If you are curious about how to
work with your app icons in
Xcode, please check out the
"What's New in Cocoa Touch
Session Recording?"
We also had a great new session
this morning that went into the
design philosophy and the
general thinking around the new
App Store this morning called
"Introducing the New App Store."
So if you haven't seen that, be
sure to check that out because
it's very interesting.
And tomorrow we have two store
kit sessions; "What's New in
Store Kit?"
and "Advanced Store Kit."
So if you want to learn more
about the API side of the
features we talked about today,
come to those sessions.
Thank you for attending our
session and we hope that you
enjoy the rest of your
conference.
[ Applause ]