>> In the next 10 minutes, we
will learn how to use alerts to
make your app better, your users
happier, and your ratings and
revenues higher.
Good alerts can accomplish that
because they are one of the most
efficient problem-solving tools
at your disposal.
They help people enjoy your app,
and navigate it easily, instead
of getting stuck in some
suboptimal state, getting
frustrated, confused, quitting
your app, de-installing your
app, and giving you one-star
ratings.
So how do you create alerts that
work?
Before you get to the creating
part, you should ask yourself a
very important question.
Should I be using an alert at
all?
Is this the best way to achieve
my goal?
Let's look at some examples of
good alert use.
The most common one you are
familiar with is to correct
errors, like this one.
Alerts are also used to request
access to user data, such as
contacts, location, or financial
information.
We provided a format for your
use, and put a lot of thought in
its content.
It explains concisely and
clearly what data is requested,
and how it will be used.
Alerts are also used to notify
people of major updates, such as
significant feature releases, or
critical security fixes.
These announcements should be
used judiciously and sparingly.
Reserve them only for problems
that merit immediate attention
or features that would really
benefit your audience, certainly
not every update merits an
alert, and on that note, let's
talk about when alerts should
not be used.
I will introduce this topic with
a very important point I would
like you to remember.
Alerts are disruptive by design.
Oops, what are you doing here?
Can't you see I'm in the middle
of a talk?
Don't you wish you could do this
to all annoying alerts?
So the lesson here is, do not
use alerts for non-essential
content.
Before putting any content in an
alert, ask yourself, do people
really need to know this, and do
they need to know this now.
If the answer to that question
is not an absolute resounding
yes, do not interrupt your
audience.
The next important point I would
like you to remember is that
alerts are lightweight by
design.
Their small format reflects and
serves the purpose of
facilitating quick, informed
decisions, so that people can
make a choice, and move on with
whatever they were doing.
Therefore, do not overload
alerts with lengthy content, or
too many choices.
These tasks are better left to
larger UI elements.
Let's look at some examples.
Alerts are not settings, nor are
they multiple choice questions.
You can see that the actions are
struggling to fit into the
provided format, and here is a
hint for you.
If your alert takes most of the
supported view port, it is time
to cut down or relegate some of
the tasks to larger elements.
Alerts are full-scale diagnostic
tools.
Do not use them to expose
technical data, especially error
codes.
Alerts are not afterthoughts.
Do not use them to fix
preventable problems.
For example, if you have
password rules, articulate them
clearly on the main screen.
You can also disallow invalid
character input.
However, the thing to not do is
to make users memorize a long,
complicated list of characters,
and then go back to fix the
problem that should not have
occurred in the first place.
To summarize, the dos and don'ts
of alerts, use them to correct
errors, request access to
customer data, or notify people
of major updates.
Do not use them for
non-essential or lengthy
content.
Do not offer complicated
choices.
And do not duplicate the tasks
of other UI elements.
Now, you have considered all
these factors and decided that
you need an alert after all.
So how do you go about writing a
successful one?
It turns out that the structure
of the alert, with its clear
separation of visual elements
already sets you on this path of
success.
Let's go back to our good alert
example, and see how we can make
use of that structure.
In the title, state your main
point in one sentence or less.
In the message details, provide
brief additional information if
necessary, such as the cause of
the error, or the reason for
your request.
Offer actions that are easy to
understand and perform.
If you have to take people
outside the app, or to a
different state, make sure to
navigate them there.
Do not leave this job to the
Back button, the Home button,
the main screen, or otherwise
leave users to find their way.
If people scan the title and the
actions, ideally, they should be
able to understand what is going
on without paying too much
attention to the message
details.
While this is not always
possible, it is a good goal to
aspire to.
And if you need a quick mnemonic
rule, a good alert answers three
key questions.
What happened?
Why people are seeing this?
And how this should proceed
based on the information they've
received.
Now that you've mastered the
structure of the alert, let's
practice and apply these
guidelines to fix some common
problems.
Let's read through this one.
"App name" cannot open this
file.
The title is accurate, but not
especially helpful.
Which file do we mean?
People may be working with
multiple files.
You may need to download the
latest available updates for the
app.
Do you want to visit the "app
name" website for more
information and troubleshooting
tips?
These instructions are vague and
tentative, and suggest multiple
outcomes, and that is also a lot
of text.
No. Yes. The actions are
difficult to understand without
going back and reading said
lengthy instructions.
Let's see how we can improve
this.
First, let's specify the file
name for clarity.
Next, let's pare down the
instructions for simplicity.
Finally, let's offer clear
actionable choices, so that
people understand what happens
when they tap on any one of
them.
Here is your before and after.
Which one do you think looks
better?
Thought so.
Now, let's take a look at an
alert that seems to be written
with all the guidelines in mind.
Let's read through this one.
Cancel download?
If you cancel now, you will not
receive this file.
Cancel? Okay [laughter].
There is nothing wrong with any
individual part, the title
states the question, the message
describes the consequences, and
even the actions use the
recommended terminology.
Cancel and okay.
However, this is a classic
example of a confusing alert
that happens even to the most
experienced developers.
So the lesson here is, even when
using guidelines, always check
the result for any ambiguity or
confusion.
Let's see how we can clarify
this one.
First, let's rephrase the title
to remove ambiguity and mention
the filename to be more
specific.
Next, let's apply similar
changes to the message details.
And for good measure, let's
reiterate the choices and the
actions, so people understand
what happens if they click on
any of them.
Here is your before and after.
And I hope you would agree that
the after looks a bit better
than the before.
Now, you have learned how to
make use of the structure, let's
talk a bit about style and
quality.
Here, I have a couple of tips
for you.
Avoid platitudes, jargon or
fillers.
All they do is take space
without adding any return value.
Use correct formatting,
spelling, and punctuation.
This seems like a very basic
piece of advice, but it will go
a very long way toward making
your alerts and your app look
polished and professional.
Finally, consider your audience.
Whether you are writing for
medical professionals, special
needs students, or even a very
smart cat who just learned how
to use an iPad, make sure that
your editorial voice matches
their needs and expectations.
In conclusion, here are the
three simple things you can do
now to make your alerts awesome.
Keep them simple and helpful.
Go practice.
Take what you learned, go
through your app, see if you
need all the alerts that you
created, and if you do, see how
you can make them work harder.
And for more information and an
in-depth look on how to write
alerts for iOS and macOS, read
the HIG available at the Apple
website.
Thank you.