[ Chatter ]
>> All right, next up is
onboarding.
We're going to discuss how to
engage people from the first
moment they open your app and
keep them coming back for more.
Please welcome, Vince Lane from
the productivity design team.
[ Applause ]
>> Hi, I'm Vince.
There we go.
All right, imagine you're
searching for an apartment.
You've been in the hunt, and
this one looks pretty good.
The price is right.
Photos show tons of natural
light, it's close to work.
So you schedule some time to
stop by and check the place out.
You bike over.
Someone buzzes you in.
You find the apartment door.
You give it a knock.
And the landlord greets you.
And before he'll even let you
pass the front door, he has some
requirements.
He wants to see a passport, a
birth certificate, and your last
four paystubs.
Now this would be a little
ridiculous, right?
You just want to check the place
out, you're not ready to commit
to anything yet.
Plus, who knows if your private
info is safe with this guy.
First impressions matter.
They matter because they could
also be your last.
People have access to millions
of apps in the App Store.
You've already passed the first
hurdle when someone installs
your app.
Great.
So prevent them from backing out
and deleting your app in the
same way you'd probably be off
to the next apartment on your
list.
And instead, start things off
with a great first impression.
Now suppose you're planning a
trip.
And a friend suggested this
travel app here.
Looks pretty good.
So the installation completes.
You tap open for the first time.
And you're met with this.
Now, does this look familiar?
Someone wants you to register
here, but there's not much info
about what this app actually
does.
Sure, you have some idea after
your friend's recommendation.
But when you open the app for
the first time and this is how
you're greeted, it still feels a
little something like this guy.
There's a chance you might back
out, delete it, and go find
something else.
Now consider this military base
with its fortified exterior, the
message to anyone on the outside
is clear, stay out, right?
Compare that to Apple Union
Square in San Francisco.
The entire front of the store
opens up to the sidewalk,
inviting passersby to wander in.
And wander in is exactly what
they do.
As people use -- as people
explore the store, they're able
to pick up and use iPhones.
They might take a new Mac for a
test drive or try on an Apple
Watch, all without obstacles or
friction.
Your first launch experience
should feel just as
frictionless.
If people are greeted with an
open, interactive experience the
very first time they tap your
icon, you're going to make a
great first impression and keep
them coming back.
So let's talk about some ways to
make that happen.
We'll be discussing some tips
for leading with content first.
How to teach new users about
your app through interaction.
And when you need to ask for
some more information up front,
some tips on timing that will
add to a great user experience.
So let's start with some
strategies for content first
approach.
Let's compare our travel app
here to another travel app.
This is Jetsetter.
The very first time you open
Jetsetter, you're immediately
greeted with this great content.
Big, beautiful images, useful
information.
You can browse this feed, of
course, or you can jump right
into search if you have
something specific in mind.
If a destination catches your
attention, you can drill in for
more photos and more details.
And it's been seconds since you
first launched this app, and
you're already using it like a
pro.
You're intrigued by all this
great content and you've already
started daydreaming about laying
on this beach.
It's only when you're ready to
book the trip that you're
prompted to register.
By now, you've got a good idea
of what the app has to offer.
You've seen the potential
benefits of registering, so this
feels like a more appropriate
time to share more details.
If you're not convinced yet,
just compare Jetsetter with our
other travel app.
Now, we've all been through some
version of that top row.
Which one of these feels more
welcoming to you?
Always lead with great content.
Show off what makes your app
great right off the bat, and let
people dig in.
Now there are some situations
where a little bit of upfront
instruction might be helpful.
And I say might because before
you start incorporating some of
the tips we're about to look at,
I want you to very carefully
consider whether any upfront
instruction is needed at all.
Let's take a quick look at the
phone app.
Now, just imagine if we designed
this with a series of first-run
tool tips.
It'd be a little ridiculous,
right?
This interface is obvious.
We know how it works.
You should strive to design your
interfaces to be as intuitive
and as easy to understand as
possible.
Ideally, no upfront instruction
is needed at all.
All right, let's take a look at
Lara Croft GO.
This is your starting point
here.
No onboarding, no instructions,
nothing to pull your attention
from this immersive experience.
You're right in the game.
But you still need to learn how
to play this game, so these
first few levels are designed to
introduce you to the basics.
Well, you only have a straight
line here, and Lara looks like
she's ready to go.
Since there are no visible
controls, you try swiping on the
screen.
And sure enough, she starts
moving in the direction you've
gestured.
You quickly discover you can
move up and down walls too.
And congratulations, you've
learned the game's navigation
controls.
All right, now you've got this
glowing tile of a head catching
your attention.
Options look pretty limited, so
let's go check it out.
Yes, you've just completed a
level.
Now, that one was pretty simple,
of course.
But it's teaching you the
basics, and you're already
playing the game.
All right, level two starts
here.
Looks like your path is cut
short, so let's try that switch.
Aha, the missing path fills in,
and you figured out another
important part about how this
game works.
Now, of course, things get a lot
more complex from here.
But you can start to see how
instruction can be layered into
an experience.
And again, no onboarding, no
tool tips or floating hands
here.
There are no barriers when you
first play Lara Croft GO.
And this approach works in all
kinds of apps, not just games.
This is streaks.
It's a simple app designed to
help you pick up new habits.
In my case as you might be able
to guess, I'm studying French,
and I'm trying to make a habit
of practicing every day.
Maybe Streaks can help.
The completion of a task is
represented by the filling in of
a ring.
So the first launch experience
conveys this in a clever way by
inviting you to fill in rings as
you proceed through this
introduction.
And you're led right into
creating your first habit.
So if your app requires a bit of
upfront education, it's going to
be a lot more compelling if it's
interactive and gives people
that sense of jumping right in.
Teach through interactive
experiences.
Now, another place you don't
want people to get stuck is with
permission requests.
You know what it's like to open
an app for the first time and
get hit with permission requests
after permission requests, sort
of like that demanding landlord
we met earlier.
So let's look at some tips for
getting this right.
This is Strava.
Strava lets you use your iPhone
to track outdoor runs and bike
rides, and it eventually asks
for access to your location,
your camera, your contacts, even
health get data.
But it doesn't ask for all of
these right away.
Instead, Strava makes requests
on an as-needed basis.
For example, it's not until
you're ready to take Strava out
for a ride for the first time
that you're prompted to share
your location.
So you hit record down at the
bottom.
We'll get you on a ride here.
Who's ready to roll?
All right, so you're going on
your ride.
And eventually, a little while
later, you're ready to wrap
things up.
We'll make it a short ride.
So you stop the ride, and you
tap save.
Now, when you're saving a ride,
you have the option to add more
details, including a photo.
It's only when you tap add a
photo that you're prompted for
access to your photo library.
And this is another great
example of a permission request
that's right in context.
So you immediately see the
benefit and no additional
explanation is necessary.
And then it's the same situation
when looking for friends on
Strava in your contacts.
The app requests permissions on
a need-to-know basis.
So you retain a sense of control
over both the experience and
your private data.
Now, there are a few apps out
there that can't offer any value
without some sort of
permissions.
This is Transit.
It lists departures of nearby
buses and trains, order based on
proximity to your current
location.
I live in San Francisco, and I
use this one all the time to get
around.
Of course, it wouldn't be able
to provide this data without
your location, so the first time
you launch the app, you are
prompted to share your location.
And as soon as you tap allow,
the map zooms in, and you're
presented with a list of nearby
routes and departure times.
So you immediately see the value
Transit will provide in exchange
for this information.
So remember, I'm sure people
understand the value of sharing
their private data with you,
ideally before you ask for it.
Once that permission has been
granted, reinforce the decision
by showing off the benefits
you'll provide with that data.
Only ask for what's needed when
it's needed.
Follow these tips, and I promise
you'll make a great first
impression.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]