[ Cheers ]
[ Applause ]
>> Hello, welcome to Session
2010, What's New in Core Data.
I'm Melissa.
I'm one of the Core Data
engineers.
And I will be joined on stage
later by Rishi, one of my
co-workers.
And we're here to talk about all
of the stuff that we've been
working on for the last year
because it's been fun for us.
And we're hoping that you'll
find it fun and useful to work
with in your applications.
And we will hope all of the
technical problems for this
presentation have already
happened.
So what have we been up to?
We've been doing some Core
Spotlight Integration.
We've added a bunch of new
indexing APIs.
And we've added a big new
feature called Persistent
history tracking.
That is what Rishi's going to
talk about.
And it's really cool and I'm
really excited to see it
presented here.
But first Alphonse says "Hi".
He's my mascot.
I couldn't do this without him.
So CoreSpotlight.
What is Core Spotlight?
Before I talk about Core
Spotlight I want to talk a
little bit about Spotlight.
Spotlight was the original
search API, and search
technology on Mac OS 10.
It was very document centric,
which meant that the search
results that you would get back
from a customer doing a search
in the Spotlight menu would
identify the document that had
been retrieved by Spotlight, but
wouldn't actually tell you where
in the document that hit came
from.
And it was not really ideal for
databases, which as we know can
have lots and lots of records in
them.
Which brings us to Core
Spotlight.
Core Spotlight was the original
search technology on iOS.
And it was much more
database-friendly.
It would return not only the
application and the document
that the user had selected, but
it would also tell you where in
that document.
It allowed for deep linking into
your application so you could
bring up exactly the results
that your user was interested in
seeing.
Now it ships on Mac OS, as well
as on iOS.
And we thought this is a great
time to integrate with it in
Core Data.
So how does Core Spotlight work?
Well it's a lot like Spotlight.
You've got an application.
It has a bunch of data in it.
The user goes into the Spotlight
menu and looks for something
that's going to be in your
application.
For example, you know, photo
from India.
And Spotlight launch services
launches your application and
you're given a user activity
that you can use to retrieve the
information about what the user
was searching for.
Popup, you know, that specific
view so your user could see it.
As I said, it's now shipping on
Mac OS as well as iOS.
And at this point the Core
Spotlight team wants me to tell
you that you can also use the
Core Spotlight API's to access
the Spotlight search indexes
from your application, which is
cool.
And it does all of this without
scattering zero-length files all
over the file system.
And I'm really hoping that at
least some of you are mentally
cheering about this because I
sure was.
So how does it work?
There's three basic components
to the Core Spotlight
integration.
First there's -- we've
repurposed the index by
Spotlight property on NS
Property Description to indicate
that a property should be pushed
into Core Spotlight.
But we need a way to specify
what should be showing up in the
Spotlight results menu.
And that is NS Entity
Description Core Spotlight
Display Name Expression.
And of course there's an
Exporter.
That whenever you do save in
your application pushes whatever
change the user has made into
the Core Spotlight Index.
Core Spotlight Display Name
Expression is kind of the
trickiest piece of this to
understand.
It's actually an instance of NS
Expression that you set as a
property on NS Entity
Description.
And it's evaluated during the
Core Spotlight index update.
With the object -- the managed
object that's being updated as
the evaluated object parameter.
And this allows you to return
anything that can be pushed in
to Core Spotlight.
Even something that's not one of
the base Core Data types.
Like for example an instance of
CS Localized String.
By and large, these expressions
are going to evaluate Keypaths
but they could be, you know,
much more interesting.
They could be built in
functions, lowercase, uppercase,
stuff like that.
Or if you're somebody like me
they could be completely random
functions that go often dig
around in your runtime to find
instances of classes and call
just random methods on them to
get their stuff back.
I think that's cool too.
And of course, there's the NS
Core Data Spotlight Delegate,
which is like the big and
complicated piece that we wrote
that does all the work.
It implements CS Searchable
Index Delegate.
It provides default
implementation of all methods,
so you can use it straight out
of the box.
It uses separate store on a
background thread so you don't
need to worry about any of the
work that's being done by the
Spotlight Exporter blocking your
main view context from getting
its work done.
You initialize it with a NS
Persistent Store Description and
a model since it needs to know
what it's working with.
And basically you tell a
Persistent Store that it should
be exporting its data to Core
Spotlight by setting the
exporter as an option when in
when you're calling NS
Persistent Store with type on
the Persistent Store
Coordinator.
The override point on the
delegate if you don't like the
default behavior is NS Data Core
Spotlight delegate attribute set
for object.
And an override might look
something like this.
Here we've got a basic method
that goes through and gets the
attribute set return by the
super class.
It looks at the object, realizes
that this is an instance of a
photo because I've got like the
photo app and those photos have
tags.
And when somebody searches for
something-- when the user
searches for something, that
returns a hit on one of those
tags, I actually want to return
the photo that has that tag
because the tag itself is not
terribly interesting.
So I go and collapse all of the
tag information on to the photo
objects itself so that the photo
will be returned when there's a
match in Spotlight.
And then I just return the
attribute set.
And that's as much code as we
expect most of you to ever have
to write for this.
So now I'm going to do a demo.
And I've got a little
application here.
Please ignore the x Code in the
background, we'll get there.
It displays photos.
If you scroll around, look at
stuff, click on things to see,
you know?
Photos of people enjoying
themselves with a little bit of
meta data information.
But here's the interesting part.
I can now come up to Spotlight
and type in for example,
something that I know is in
Spotlight and it automatically
activates my application and
calls the application continue
user activity method with an NS
user activity.
And here I've broken in that
method so let's see what's going
on.
Well, somebody opened something
and I'm going to go dig around
in that user activities user
info because that's where all
the interesting stuff is and dig
out the identifier.
And if I print that identifier
we can see that well, the
identifier and the user info is
something that looks an awful
lot like a managed object ID
string representation.
So I'm going to turn that into a
URI and ask the persistent store
coordinator to turn that into a
managed object ID.
And then I'm just going to
continue and hey wow, I've
opened the photo that my user
requested.
Lovely, relaxing view.
And that sort of how the Core
Spotlight Integration works.
We do most of the work, you need
to implement a method that does
stuff.
So that's the Core Spotlight
Integration.
Some totally non-sharp corners,
stuff we've made easy for you.
If you decide that you want to
enable the Core Spotlight
Integration and pass an exporter
to as one of the options when
you add your store to the
persistent store coordinator.
We will automatically start
exporting to Core Spotlight on
your application's first launch.
And we will continue exporting
until we have exported all of
the data even if your
application is exited, if the
user exits your application in
the meantime.
We use the Persistent History
Tracking feature to ensure that
all of the data is pushed.
Even if your application
crashes, exits, whatever that
doesn't quite work in the seed
but it will eventually.
Some slightly sharper corners,
the Core Spotlight and Spotlight
integration aren't mutually
exclusive, you can't do both.
If you try setting both entities
to Core Spotlight, Display Name
Expression, and the property is
stored in External Record, the
model compiler is going to
complain at you.
And we don't currently track the
results of batch operations.
Some slightly sharp corners.
This first one is something I
discovered while debugging
because I built all of my unit
tests in a separate framework,
which is run by XCTest, which
doesn't have this entitlement,
which made it very confusing as
to why I couldn't talk to
Spotlight.
Whatever application is trying
to talk to Spotlight, needs to
have the
com.apple.application-identifier
entitlement.
Most of you are going to get
this by default, but if you're
writing your unit tests, which
are run by XCTtest be aware of
this.
And of course you're going to
need to handle the search
result.
You need to implement
Application, Continue User
Activity on your application
delegate and you know, put
whatever you'd like in there.
We saw this on screen or the
demo, but I'm just walk through
it here.
This is the method you'd be
implementing.
Pretty simple, grab the User
Activity user info.
The identifier manage object ID
is stashed in there under KCS
Searchable Item Activity
Identifier.
Just turn that into a managed
object ID and then you can do
whatever you'd like.
Watch a new window, zoom to the
correct view, whatever.
There are however some really
sharp corners involved.
Which is that if you were using
the old Spotlight integration,
it's going to be up to you to
delete your old reference files
if you had them on disc, because
we can't know if there was
semantic meaning to those.
And the Core Spotlight API's are
x86 only, which means that this
feature is x86 only.
So it's time to upgrade your
applications people.
And that's Core Spotlight.
We've also added a New Indexing
API.
So what is indexing?
Indexing is a way that allows
you to configure your database
to do faster searching.
You can have multiple indexes,
each of which can have multiple
columns, and a column can
actually belong to multiple
indexes.
So this allows you to set up a
lot of indexes that the database
can use to choose the most
efficient index for whatever
query it's trying to execute.
It will basically look at the
aware clause and say, oh I'm
trying to use these columns I'll
use this index.
And now I'm going to do a little
bit of a digression on indexing
for those of you, you know,
aren't database heads.
The basic form of indexing that
supported everywhere by
everything is a Binary Index.
But these are very strict
comparison only.
They basically look at the bits
and say are these bits the same?
And if not, you know, it's not
an index head.
But over time more types of
indexes have become popular and
something that's really
especially nowadays is super
useful is an RTree Index, which
is a type of index that's
optimized for doing range base
searching.
So a binary index sort of looks
like this.
This is the kind of data you
might have, a bunch of -- you
know, unit dimensional stuff.
And if you build a BTree on it
you end up with something that
looks a lot like this.
You know for every node that all
of the nodes -- child nodes to
the left are smaller valued than
the parent node and all the
nodes to the right are larger
valued and you just navigate
down very, very simply.
But RTree Data often looks a lot
more like this.
You end up having lots of, you
know, odd shapes,
multidimensional things.
They're often overlapping in
weird and odd ways.
And there's no really great way
to organize those in a unit
directional linear Binary tree.
And RTree Data often is stored
more like this.
You have a range zero, which is
the minimum bounding blocks
around all of its subcomponents
or its set elements.
For example range element fully
contains the ranges R6 and R10.
And R6 in turn has a single
child R7, which has more
children.
This is actually a slightly
unbalanced RTree but oh well,
we'll live with it.
The current indexing APIs, well
we have two of them.
You can create a single property
index by calling an NS Attribute
Description is Indexed.
Set that property and we'll
create an index on it.
If you want to do a multi column
index you'll call NS Entity
Description compound Indexes.
And that allows you to create an
index that has, you know, three,
four, five columns in it.
But both of these API's
automatically and only create a
Binary Index in ascending order.
And we kind of wanted to evolve
the Core Data APIs, make them
ore powerful, a lot of them
specifying new and interesting
things, more configurable.
So we've added a bunch of new
model classes.
First is NS Fetch Index
Description, NS Fetch Element
Description, and we've added a
new method on NS Entity
Description indexes which takes
a Fetch Index Description as
it's -- an array of Fetch index
descriptions as its parameter.
And we've added some functions
to control whether the database
should or should not use a
specific index when its
evaluating a given query.
And we've added index by, which
allows you to say, hey really
use this index.
And no index has existed for
awhile and it's a way of saying
I know better than you and I
know better than your query
optimizer, don't use an index
for this specific component of
the where clause.
NS Fetch Index Element
Description is sort of the basic
component.
It allows you to specify an
Index Element, basically a
single property.
You can specify the type of
index that should be created on
that property, whether it's
going to be Binary or an RTree.
And if it's Binary index it also
has you specify a direction,
ascending or descending.
And this can be important if
you're doing certain types of
searches.
For example if you're doing a
male search you want to start
with the most recent data first,
instead of the oldest data
first.
So direction changes the order
in which the database will look
at the contents of the index.
A Fetch Index Description allows
you to combine a bunch of Fetch
Index Elements into a single
index, which you'll give a name
and optionally you can set a
predicate that says only put
rows matching this predicate
into the index.
It also does some validation of
the index composition to make
sure the index you've created is
reasonable.
Some Sharp Corners here, you
can't mix and match element
types right now.
It's either going to be an RTree
or a Binary index.
Range indexes can only be
created on numeric properties
less than or equal to 32 bit.
That's a restriction of the
underlying SQLite database.
If you're creating your own
incremental store and that's a
restriction -- that's a problem
for you, let us know and we'll
see what we can do about it.
But Range -- properties that are
being put in a Ranged Index also
can't be optional.
Range of null is a little bit
undefined right now.
And if you're building your
model in code and we know some
of you do it, and I've helped
some of you at previous WWDC's.
If you change your entities
structurally after you've set
indexes, then we're just going
to drop the index.
And that actually applies for
the entire entity hierarchy.
If you add or remove an entity
in the hierarchy or add or
remove properties on any of
those entities, we can no longer
be sure the index is valid so
we're just going to drop it.
Do it last.
As you may know from previous
versions, changing the indexes
on an entity doesn't actually
change the entities version
Hash, which means that there's
not going to be migration when
the user first launches your new
version of your application with
the new indexes.
So there's not going to be a
performance head.
On the other side it's not going
to cause a migration so they're
not going to get updated
indexes.
If you want to cause the index
of migration to happen and for
the indexes to be updated,
you'll need to call the --
Update the model's version Hash
Identifier and that will trigger
a migration.
The SQL store is going to ignore
any indexes it doesn't
understand.
So what that means is that if
you open your database after you
think you've added indexes and
don't see them, go look at the
application console, it probably
told you why you're not seeing
them.
And I'm going to do another demo
here.
I have a model here.
And I'm actually not going to
work with my live model because
this is a demo and I will
inevitably typo something, but
adding a new index in the new
modeling tools is actually
pretty simple.
You select the entity that you
want to add an index to and just
come down here to add entity and
you can now see that it has an
Add Fetch Index option.
And you just add one, call it by
Location, and I can add a couple
of properties to it here -- the
latitude and longitude
properties.
And if come over here and select
the photo, you'd come in here
and change the Version Hash
Modifier.
And now the next time a user
launches an application that
uses this version of the model,
they're going to be using the
new RTree index.
Of course I am going to just
going to run my demo application
which already had that built in.
And --
-- I'm going to come down here
and grab the Predicate that I
have carefully set aside -- oh I
forgot one thing.
I'm going to come up here and
edit the scheme, because we want
to see what Core Data is sending
to the database.
And I've got the Com Apple SQL
Debug Argument Set.
And you'll notice -- for those
of you who are familiar with SQL
Debug as a feature in Core Data,
you're probably most familiar
with 1 and 2 as the numbers --
the levels you're going to be
setting.
We've added a new level 4, which
will actually print the query
plan that SQLite is using as
well as all of the statements
that Core Data is sending to the
database.
So I'm going to run my
application with that version
set to 4.
Come back, reset that predicate,
and run the search.
And now we can come and we see
the last search.
It's actually kind of more
interesting and I'm going to
come over here and I've actually
copied and pasted an earlier
version into Text Edit, because
I could enlarge the text there.
But you can see I'm now doing a
sub Select against a separate
table, Z Photo by Location.
And if I look down in the query
plan, you can see that this is a
virtual table index.
So that's basically routing the
location query, the latitude
query down onto a separate RTree
table.
And well, we can see up here
that it says it took 0.056
seconds for 16 rows.
And if I go compare this to the
version without the RTree, well
there's the query we were
originally doing, Z Longitude
between this and this.
And we can see that it took
0.062 seconds for 16 rows.
So you got to do about a 10
percent performance improvement
on a laptop with an SSD Fast
Cash, all that kind of stuff.
So it's about a 10 percent
improvement your devices are
actually going to -- and it's
also a very small data set.
Your devices with a larger data
set are really going to
appreciate having RTree's to
search against instead of
regular Binary Indexes.
And --
I think I'm done here.
So that is RTree searching.
I have one more slide before I
hand you over to Rishi.
We've also added some
miscellaneous new stuff.
Basically new attribute types.
We've added NSUUIDA Attribute
Type and a NSURL Attribute type
backed by the UUID and URL value
classes respectively.
[ Applause ]
You appreciate the work we do.
That makes us feel good.
And now I'm going to hand you
over --
>> Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Hi everybody I'm Rishi Verma
and I'll be showing you
Persistent History Tracking.
So let's talk a little bit about
your app.
So you've developed these
amazing apps and hopefully
you've adopted the NS Persistent
Container we introduced last
release.
So you've got a View Context set
up and a Background Context.
And you've got a Shared
Container where you've set up
your Persistent Store.
Now your view context is one
connection and your background
context is another.
And maybe you've got your
background context downloading
contend from the remote site
that you have set up.
Now you're a very diligent
developer and you've gone out
and created a Document
Extension, a Shared Extension,
and a Photo Editing Extension.
Now all of these connections to
your persistent store could be
running in any process since
they're extensions, or they
could be coming from our app
from various context.
And you may not know exactly
where this data is coming from.
Well, let's break it down a
little bit and see what happens.
So sorry, so here we are in your
app and the user is looking at
your view context and in the
meantime your background context
is downloading info from some
remote source.
Unfortunately a common thing
that we've seen is that your
Background Context may be
ingesting and your View Context
may not know about these
objects, or it may not even care
about these objects.
But as your Save Notifications
come in, you're ingesting them
anyways.
And so you're going to be
missing some changes, if you
missed out new Background
Context, because they're really
easy to generate at this time
but you may miss out on Batch
Updates, Batch Deletes, which
don't generate a Save
notification.
Now the user's gone into Safari
and decided to share something.
This writes to the database and
when you're developer comes back
to the app -- or when you're
user comes back to the app, you
don't know what's changed.
You know something's changed,
but what exactly you don't know.
And so you have to rescan the
entire database and see what has
changed since you last were
there.
And unfortunately sometimes our
apps crash.
It may be due to the user
quitting your app while a
Background Contact was going.
And when your app comes back up,
your Background Context doesn't
know necessarily where it left
off, scanning your local
database.
So it'll have to check with
remote content and rescan the
entire local database to see
where it needs to be picked up
again.
Let's break this example down
just a little bit more.
So we have an app, and it
decides to load some data.
So the Background Context loads
some data and the View Context
gets updated.
Now when the user suspends the
app, and the document extension
comes up, we'll see that data
inserts two new objects.
And then my Share Extension
comes along, updates an object
and inserts another one.
And so does my Photos Extension.
Once all of these are done I'll
come back to my app and notice
that some of the data is stale.
So our app here only knows about
these original six objects.
The rest of the database is
actually modified or it actually
doesn't know about these
objects.
So it has to go through and scan
everything and see what's
relevant to that View Context or
that Background Context.
Now we've introduced NS
Persistent History.
It's rather simple.
Grab your Container, grab your
Store Description and voila.
Set the option NS Persistent
History Tracking to true and we
will now track all of your
changes to your database.
So let's go back to that
previous-- thank you.
[ Applause ]
So we'll go back to that
previous example.
And now in my View Context and
Background Context load data,
we'll see that it happens within
a transaction.
And this transaction's written
to my database.
And I can see that it was done
by the Background Context and in
my app.
Now when I hop out of my app and
the user goes into a Document
Extension --
We'll see that this also
generates a transaction and so
on with my share extension.
And also the Share Extension
will note that there was a
modification and not an insert
here.
And now with a Photos Extension
we'll also see the fourth
transaction come in and we'll
see that it was done in photos.
So now when my app is being
brought back to the foreground,
I do still have still data, but
now I know where I am in the
history table and can simply go
from transaction 1 to 4.
And voila I've updated.
So we've introduced a new Store
Request for you to fetch your
history.
It's called NS Persistent
History Change Request.
You can simply start it up with
either a date, a token, or a
transaction.
And you can simply set the
result type as well.
As simple as a status, the count
of change is available.
Or you can get nitty-gritty and
get all the transactions and all
the changes.
Also with a change request we
allow you to purge your history.
So we want you to start this off
and you can delete the history
prior to date, a token, or a
transaction.
Now your Persistent History is
linear so this way it will keep
it short.
One of the caveats we want you
to keep in mind when pruning
your history is that you should
have a gatekeeper.
Single place where this should
be done so that it knows that
you've consumed the history you
need, your clients have consumed
it, and you no longer are
removing anything that is
relevant to someone else in your
app, all right?
And then now we have NS
Persistent History Transaction.
This is a large data blob that
covers who did the transaction
to your database.
So as you can see we have a
Store ID, a Bundle ID, a Process
ID, but we also have a Token.
Since your history is linear, we
provide you a Token that you can
encode to disc, so that when
your app exits you can keep
track of where your app was in
the history.
Simply re-launch your app, pull
your token, and fetch your
history based on that and you're
good to go.
Now, also in the transaction we
allow you -- the author, we want
you to go onto your Manage
Object Context and tell us who
is the author of this context
and this Save Batch Update or
Batch Delete.
And so we also allow you to go
onto the Manage Object Context
and set the Transaction Author.
Do this before your save or
executing a request and we'll
take this string, put in a
transaction, so you can identify
who did what to your database at
a later time.
And as part of every transaction
there is a set of changes.
A change represents a single
thing that was done to one
object.
So they'll be many changes for
every transaction and here we'll
have inserts, and updates, and
deletes.
In the case of an update, we'll
tell you which properties were
updated -- either attributes or
relationships, and then in the
case of a delete we'll tell you
what the tombstone is.
It's a set of attributes that
you can set in the model editor
that allow you to identify the
object post mortem.
It's no longer in your database
so the object ID isn't as
relevant anymore, but with a
tombstone you can still identify
that object and be able to
process it later.
Now here we are in the model
editor.
And I have a unique identifier
for this entity.
And it would be great if I could
tombstone it.
So we simply go in and mark it
Preserve After Deletion.
And it's that simple and it will
show up in my tombstone.
And so with that I'd like to
show you a quick Demo.
So I have a simple app here.
It takes a post I have and puts
it on my social media feeds.
I've set it up with a few
buttons here.
A download button that will go
on a background context and
ingest from the Cloud.
And a background task that will
go out and post all of my stuff.
And I've also got a tab where I
can go and see the history.
Currently in my code I have Use
Persistent History set to False,
but I've enabled it for my store
so that we can see what's
changed.
So here I am and I'll have a
user post.
And this user said, "This demo
is amazing!"
Awesome. And I can also go and
download one from the
background.
And we can see that I've labeled
where the post came from.
The first one comes from the
user, the next one comes from
the background.
But now let's hop out and go to
the Share Extension.
And let's share about Apple here
real quick.
So I can post about this and see
in my app.
And now when we get back to my
app -- oh wait, I lost some
data, this is really odd.
It must have something wrong.
But if I go back to the history
I can see that I had a post
within the app and I had remote
content and I even can see the
Share Extension.
However I'm not seeing that
here, like the user I start
adding data and trying to figure
out what's wrong with this UI.
And my Persistent History once
again is showing everything.
Oh wait, that's weird.
All of a sudden my app has hit
some refresh that I've
downloaded into it based on some
view where I finally go and hit
the database and re-fetch
everything.
Because that's the only way I
can solve this problem sometimes
and that's frustrating to our
users.
But what happens if we turn on
Persistent History and no longer
have to track things like that?
So I'll simply turn this on.
So as you can see here real
quick, I have my Background
Context set up and my View
Context set up and I've also got
them listening to each other.
But I also have some Transaction
Author set.
And I just want to show you how
simple that is so that we can
see this going forward.
OK, so let's stop the app real
quick and re-launch.
And here we are with our app
using History at this time.
And let's go to that troublesome
case of sharing a post.
Well, High Sierra looks pretty
cool, so let's share about that
real quick.
All right, shared about that.
Real quick let's just share
about one more thing.
The cool new watchOS.
And now when we get back to the
app,
voila. There they are.
All I've done is absorb the
history, when my view reloaded,
and we can jump to that code
real quick.
So previously if I was using
Fetch Hit -- not using
Persistent History, I was
fetching everything, but now
that I am all I'm doing is
fetching the history and
absorbing the merged context
from the History.
And it gives me a much smaller
subset and I no longer have to
scan the entire database to see
what was different.
[ Applause ]
And so to recap it's rather
easy.
Simple to enable Persistent
History.
It's just one option on your
store.
It really uncovers all those
missing changes.
And you may have been generating
background context, you may just
not realize that you're missing
a notification, you've harnessed
Batch Updates, Batch Deletes,
which don't generate
notifications.
So they uncover all of that.
And you'll never be in the dark
again about changes to your
database.
Two caveats to mention about
using persistent history -- the
first one is about Migration.
We will preserve as much of your
history as possible on migration
except for two cases.
One is if you remove entities
from your model and we already
have history on these entities,
we'll have to remove that
history for those entities and
that creates a gap.
The other one is for tombstones.
For tombstones you don't want to
have certain data there after
awhile to identify the object.
Maybe it's become a security
concern for you.
So you've called the tombstone.
So we'll do the same and we'll
remove that tombstone value out
from the model.
But if that removes anything
that will leave a gap in your
history, we'll also then only
preserve your history to the
last complete transaction.
This way you can go and follow
the history without falling into
a trap where I am missing
changes once again because of a
gap.
As far as performance there's a
slight impact on every save and
every batch-operation you do.
According to the size of your
save and your batch operation
we'll do a slight calculation of
what changed and write that to
the database.
However, once your operation is
complete all of that memory that
we used is returned back to you.
There's also small storage
overhead, but your history can
be purged, so this makes it
really easy for you to reclaim
that space once you've consumed
the history.
And that's Persistent History
Tracking.
[ Applause ]
Now just to summarize what we've
gone over today.
Melissa went over Core
Spotlight.
It's really easy to adopt, easy
to share your data with
Spotlight, and it gives you deep
linking.
So your users can find their
data in your app anywhere on the
phone.
And the New Indexing API makes
your searches faster and just
makes your app that much faster.
And lastly, Persistent History
allows you to know who's always
done it, never be lost, always
know who's done what to your
database.
One PSA before we go.
Please file bugs.
Let us know if you run into an
issue.
Let us know if you want
something.
Go to bugreport.apple.com.
We are listening.
So please go and visit.
For more information check out
the www.DC website.
And for some related sessions we
had "What's New in Cocoa"
earlier today, so go check out
that video.
We also have "What's New in
Foundation" coming up next.
And we have some cool stuff on
"What's New in Core Spotlight"
later on Thursday.
And check out the "Cocoa
Development Tips" early on
Friday morning.
Thank you very much.
[ Applause ]