>> Hello and welcome to Deep
Linking on tvOS.
Today we will be looking at best
practices for supporting deep
links in your tvOS app.
So what is a deep link?
A deep link is a URL that your
application knows how to open.
We call these links in deep
because they often refer to
content that's a few levels down
in your App2i.
Instead of manually navigating
through several screens, a user
can jump immediately to the
content they want by using the
deep link.
Deep link URLs can be sent to
your app from various parts of
the system or even other
applications.
One common source of deep links
is your application's top shelf
extension.
If you have a top shelf
extension, it communicates with
your app using deep links.
The code [inaudible] handles
links from the top shelf can
also be used to handle links
from any other source.
If you're not familiar with a
top shelf, here's an example of
the top shelf extension for the
iTunes movie sound.
Each item in the top shelf will
open a different movie in the
iTunes movie app.
Because these links are meant
for your application, we
recommend that you use universal
links.
Universal links can also be used
in your iOS app, if you have
one.
Unlike rolling your own custom
URL scheme, universal links
ensure that the link is always
routed to your application.
And that the data is in a format
your application expects.
For more information about
universal links, see the web
page at this URL.
So, now that you know what a
deep link is and where they come
from, let's take a look at what
you should do when your
application is asked to open
one.
The most important part is to
take the user to the link
content immediately, without any
loading screens or animated
transitions.
You should avoid any alerts
asking if the user is sure that
they want to open the link or
sure that they want to start
playing the video.
It's also important to make sure
that when the user leaves link
content, they're able to orient
themselves in your app.
Even when jumping somewhere
directly, the user should always
know where they are and how they
got there.
How should you display deep link
content?
Well, it depends on the link.
Let's take a look at the top
shelf items again.
Each top shelf item supports two
URLs, the displayURL and the
playURL.
The displayURL is opened when
the user presses a select
button, and this should take the
user to a detail page for the
top shelf item.
And typically this detail page
will include a way to play the
item, if the item is a video.
The playURL is opened when the
user presses the Play button.
This is a shortcut that lets the
user immediately start video
playback for the item.
Remember, the displayURL should
take the user to a detail page
for the item.
Menuing out of this detail page
should take the user back to
your application's main screen.
Now it could be that the user
would normally have to navigate
through several levels to get to
the detail page from the main
screen, but they shouldn't have
to take multiple steps to back
out of a deep link.
Instead, the first Menu press
should take them back to the top
level of your application.
Because it's the top level, a
second Menu press should exit
the app and return to the tvOS
home screen.
And here's an illustration of
what that looks like.
Here, I've opened a deep link in
a simple video app.
The first screen I'm taken to is
a detail page for the video I've
selected.
Pressing Menu once takes me back
to my app's main screen, which
shows a grid of all the videos
that I can watch.
Pressing Menu again will exit my
app and take me back to the tvOS
home screen.
Now let's look at how to handle
a playURL.
Remember, this should
immediately begin video playback
for the item.
Your app should start with a
black screen and then fade in
the video.
Try to avoid any visible
transitions or user interaction
and this is especially important
for resuming playback of a video
that the user's already started
watching.
Pressing Menu to exit playback
should take the user to the same
detail page you would have shown
if the displayURL had been sent.
From there, the navigation is
the same as before.
Menuing out of the detail page,
it should go to your apps main
screen and a second Menu press
should return to the tvOS home
screen.
And here's an illustration of
what that looks like.
You can see that the first
screen is a video playback and
then behind that, it's the same
hierarchy as if we had opened
the displayURL.
Now let's take a quick look at a
demo to really see these
concepts in action.
Here's a simple app that lets me
play some of my favorite videos
from WWDC.
I can get to the videos from
within the app, but there's also
a top shelf extension that lets
me jump to the videos directly
from the tvOS home screen.
If I press select on a top shelf
item, I'm taken directly to the
detail page for that video.
If I go back to the top shelf --
And press play on a different
item, the app starts playing
that video.
Menuing out of playback takes me
to the detail page for the item
I was just watching.
You'll remember that this isn't
the same item I was looking at
when I was last in the app and
that's because when the app
opened the link from the top
shelf, it reconfigured its UI to
display the link content.
Menu again takes me out of the
detail page and into the app's
main screen.
Pressing Menu a third time exits
the app and takes me back to the
tvOS home screen.
Let's take a quick look at the
code that handles deep linking
in this app.
The work happens in the app
delegate, specifically, the
application open url with
options method.
First, when we reconfigure our
UI to display a deep link, we
want to do so without animation.
This means that the content will
already be displayed when the
system switches to our
application.
Next, we want to tear down any
UI that the user may have
navigated to in a previous
session with the app.
This app is built using a
navigation controller, so all we
have to do is pop back to the
root view controller, which is
the app's main screen.
And now, we want to push a
detail controller for the URL
onto the nav stack.
We want to do this even if we're
ultimately handling the playURL,
and that way the detail
controller will be there if the
user menu's out of playback.
And we'll push the detail
controller by performing the
same segue that would be
triggered if the user selected
one of the collection view cells
on the app's main screen.
Finally, if we're handling the
playURL, we want to push a
player view controller on top of
the detail view controller.
And we'll do this, again by
performing the same segue that
would be triggered if the user
had selected the Play button on
the detail screen.
In summary, deep links provide a
great way for users to quickly
navigate to content that may be
deep within your app.
When opening a deep link you'll
provide the best experience by
taking the user to the linked
content immediately and
providing them with a
predictable way to get back.
For more information, please
visit this website.