[ Cheers ]
>> Whether looking for the
latest TV show to watch or the
best place to grab lunch, you
rely on the people around you
for recommendations.
By offering the ability to share
on Your App, you can empower
your users to give contextual
recommendations.
But there are some important
things to consider before you
offer the ability to share.
First is the content.
In Your App, what will you want
your user to share?
Is it an image or a video, or
maybe even an experience that
they've had in Your App?
Next is placement.
Where in Your App is the best
place to offer the ability to
share?
If you share from a certain
screen, is it contextual?
Will the user know exactly what
will be passed to the recipient?
Timing is another important
aspect to building a great
sharing experience.
It needs to be, when a user is
completely connected to the
content they are wanting to
share; and at that moment,
think, "My friend Kate would
love this."
The developers of Crossy Road
have a great implementation that
has narrowed all three of these
areas.
They started with an experience.
Now, it's quite common to share
your progress in a game, but
losing in Crossy Road is
actually quite comical.
They quickly realized that
people are going to want to
share that moment and created a
photograph representation and
previewed it, ready for sharing.
The timing, content and
placement were all great.
Think about the user of Your
App.
When are they most emotionally
attached to the experience and
going to want to share it?
Another important aspect of
sharing is placement.
It doesn't make sense for a
sharing button in a list view
here; but on a detail view, it
does.
As I find a session I'm
interested in, I might think of
someone else that could be
interested and can very quickly
share it.
The way you offer the ability to
share in Your App is with an
action button.
This is the universal control
used by all apps to access
sharing.
A great place for an action
button in a detail view like
this is in the title bar.
It helps communicate to the user
that you can share all the
information in this view.
On tapping that button, you can
call a UIActivityViewController.
This will display the user's
sharing options.
By default, the system has some
built-in sharing options, like
messages, mail and notes; but
other options will populate here
from apps that have implemented
a share extension.
When creating the
UIActivityViewController, you
can parse in pretty much any
object, like a string, image or
URL.
But the best way to share the
content of Your App is to use
the universal link.
A universal link looks like a
URL, but instead launches Your
App.
At this stage, you might be
asking, "Why share a URL?
This is not a Web page."
Well, you have to consider the
person receiving the shared
information.
They may not have Your App
installed; so when tapping a
universal link when Your App is
not installed, it will fall back
to Safari, making it possible
for people with Your App to
share content with new people
that do not need Your App to
view the content.
Then if a new user receives a
link to the content in Your App,
an app banner can be displayed
in Safari, and it's a great way
to increase awareness of
innovative experience to draw
new users of Your App.
Another way you can increase the
sharing experience for the
recipient is to use Mockup in
Open Graph.
Then the content shared in
iMessage can be displayed in a
rich format; so instead of
looking like this, it can look
like this -- with an image
preview and title.
The recipient of this message is
much more likely to tap and
follow this link.
So in summary, think about the
content and experiences in Your
App.
What will your user like to
share; and when is the most
meaningful time to share?
Do they know enough about the
content to want to share it?
Use the action button to launch
sharing and consider the
placement of that button for
context.
Universal links will work with
recipients that don't have Your
App, and app banners can guide
them to Your App.
Finally, mock up your Web page
with Open Graph for rich sharing
in iMessage.
For more information, see the
resources section of this video.
Thank you, and feel free to
share it!