>> What are deep links, and how
can they be used to extend the
presence of your app?
Let's start with your app.
It consists of information like
videos, photos, or maybe places
and locations, as well as
functions like watching a video,
getting directions, or sharing
information.
The typical user experience
involves knowing that the
content or function exists in
your app; then, navigating
through some hierarchy of use in
order to find it.
This is called the user journey
or user activity.
Deep links are a way to offer
direct access to the content and
functions in your app.
The way it works is your app is
launched, you receive a link,
and the app displays the
content.
The same can be done to complete
a function in your app
automatically.
Here's an example of launching a
video from a deep link.
Note the transitions to orient
the user where they are within
the app.
This helps the user establish
their place and subtly reminds
them of how they can navigate
back.
The way you format a deep link
is called a Universal Link.
This is a secure mapping that
launches your app.
Best of all, they are universal,
and if your app is not
installed, it can always fall
back to Safari.
Here's what it looks like.
You have a scheme like https, a
domain, which is the same as
your website, and a path to the
resource.
The way you get started with
Deep Links is you add an
entitlement for all web domains
that your app supports.
You create an app-site
association file, which is an
adjacent file which contains
data about the URLs that your
app can handle.
You then upload that
app-site-association file to
your web server and implement
the continueUserActivity method
in your App Delegate.
This will pass you a
UserActivity object, which will
contain a URL for your Universal
Link.
There are many times you are
going to want a deep link to
somewhere in your app, and by
using Universal Links, you have
one clean and simple way of
doing that.
This presents many opportunities
to help new users discover your
app through its content.
For example, you can enable a
user to share content on social
media, in messaging or email
with Universal Link.
You can create those links on
the web, on your website, or
others can link to it from their
website, and it can be
catalogued in Search like
Spotlight.
Universal Links are also a way
to encourage more engagement of
you app.
The first way is to have your
app be recommended in Siri App
Suggestions and Hand Off by
registering your own
NSUserActivities.
You can create Deep Links in a
lock screen, which to make your
content, just a swipe and tap
away.
You can launch straight to the
content of your app from the App
icon with Quick Actions.
If your app contains content
supported by SiriKit, you can
map these to Universal Links.
Other apps can contain your
Universal Links, which can pass
information to your app.
If you integrate with the TV
app, then you can use Universal
Links.
A caveat here is that animation
is not necessary because the
system readies the interface for
video content before launching
your app.
So, in summary, create Deep
Links to all the app's content
and functions that it makes
sense for; create a catalog of
these using Universal Links;
expose all your links to
increase discoverability and
engagement of your content.
Finally, when launching a
Universal Link, use animation to
help keep the user oriented.
For more information, see the
resource section of this video.
Thank you.