>> Welcome to Now Playing and
Remote Commands on tvOS.
I'm Justin Voss, an engineer on
tvOS and in this talk we'll
cover how you can provide great
metadata and playback
experiences for your viewers.
First, let's talk about
providing Now Playing
information.
Having accurate and complete
metadata about your content will
help viewers to understand what
they're watching across a
variety of interfaces across
tvOS and iOS.
The metadata you provide is
displayed in several places.
For video content, the built-in
AVPlayerViewController displays
metadata along the top of the
video screen.
For both video and audio content
the TV Remote app for iOS would
both display metadata and
playback controls.
And for audio content, your
metadata will be displayed in a
badge in the corner of the
screen and as a full-screen
display when the user is idle.
Let's look at some screenshots
of these to better understand
them.
In this screenshot, you can
already tell that we're watching
a WWDC talk from last year
because the metadata onscreen
makes that super clear.
This is an example of using the
built-in AVPlayerViewController
for video content.
Here you can see the same talk,
but displayed in the TV Remote
app for iOS.
You can also see the playback
controls which we'll cover later
in the talk.
For audio content, when the Now
Playing information changes the
listener will see a notification
on their screen with the updated
metadata.
In this screenshot here, you can
see what this would look like if
we were listening to an audio
only version of that WWDC talk.
Finally, if the user puts down
the remote for a while tvOS will
automatically display the Now
Playing metadata in a
full-screen view like you see
here which really shows off the
artwork.
So, hopefully I've convinced you
that providing the complete set
of Now Playing information is
worth your time.
Let's talk about some of the
different ways you can do that.
You have a few choices so it
depends on what kind of
technology you're using in your
app.
Those of you using TVML can add
metadata using the MediaItem
JavaScript object.
This object has several
properties on it for Now Playing
info, including a title,
subtitle and description, you
can provide a URL to an artwork
image and you can even provide
information about the content
rating such as PG-13 or R and
whether the content is explicit.
In the code sample, here you can
see that I'm creating a
MediaItem object with a URL to a
video and then configuring a
title and description on it and
providing a URL to an artwork
image.
If you're using AVKit to play
your content you'll want to use
the AV metadata item class to
provide Now Playing info.
For each piece of metadata you
want to provide, such as a title
or artwork, etcetera you'll
create an AV mutable metadata
item and configure several
properties on it.
You provide an identifier which
tells AVKit what kind of
metadata this represents.
This is how we know to tell the
difference between the object
that represents a title versus
the description and so on.
You provide the value of the
metadata itself, which may be a
string or raw data bytes.
You should set the
extendedLanguageTag to specify
what language the metadata is
intended for.
Unless you have a good reason to
do otherwise we strongly
recommend that you use the value
und which means undefined.
The way this property works is
that it will only be visible to
the user if the user's locale
matches the metadata's locale.
So, for example, if you had a
movie that was produced in the
USA you may be tempted to
provide the title of that movie
with the language tag of English
since the title is in English.
But if you did that then a
viewer in Germany wouldn't see
any title at all because the
metadata language doesn't match
their language.
But if you had used the tag und
then everyone will see the
metadata regardless of their
language settings.
Finally, in some cases you need
to give us a hint about how to
interpret the value you've
provided.
In the case of providing artwork
image you'll give us the raw
bytes of the image as the value
and then use the dataType to
tell us if the image is a JPEG
or a PNG.
Let's look at some code samples
to get a feel for how this
works.
Here you can see the code where
I'm creating an AV playerItem
and giving it a title and
description.
In the first large code block
I'm creating an
AVMutableMetadataItem to
represent the title.
The first thing that I do is I
set the identifier to
AVMetadataCommon
IdentifierTitle so that AVKit
knows that this metadata item is
the title.
Then I set the actual value as a
string.
The AV metadata item API
requires these values to be NS
object types so casting the
[inaudible] string to an
NSString.
Finally, I'm setting the
extendedLanguageTag to und
because the title of this talk
should appear the same
worldwide.
In the second large code block,
I'm doing most of the same
things to assign the
description.
Other than providing a different
value you can see that on this
line I'm setting the identifier
to AVMetadataCommon
IdentifierDescription so that
AVKit knows how to interpret
this item.
Finally, on the last line I
assign an array of these
metadata items to the AV
playerItem's external metadata
property.
If you wanted to provide the
release date of your content as
a metadata item you can do that
if you format your release date
as a string in a specific
format.
This code sample shows you how
you can do that.
Here you see that I'm creating
the date object for an arbitrary
date.
Then I create a date formatter
and provide a specific date
format string here on this line.
To create the metadata item, I
use the identifier
AVMetadataCommon
IdentifierCreationDate and
finally, I use the date
formatter to convert the date
object into a formatted string
and cast that string as an
NSString.
Now in AVPlayerViewController
viewers will be able to see the
release year of the video
alongside the other Now Playing
info.
Finally, here's an example of
how to provide image metadata
for your content.
Here you can see that the first
thing I need to do is to get my
image as a data object.
I'm doing that by loading the
image from a JPEG that's in my
app bundle, but you could get
your artwork from any source.
Then to create the metadata item
the first thing I need to
specify is my identifier, which
in this case should be
AVMetadataCommon
IdentifierArtwork.
Next, I provide the artwork data
itself and cast the Swift data
object to an NSData.
Finally, to indicate what kind
of image this is I need to set
the dataType property.
Since I know this image is a
JPEG I'm going to provide this
constant value here to indicate
that.
Okay to give you a visual
reference of where some of these
items appear onscreen here's a
screenshot of the
AVPlayerViewController with some
annotations on it.
The color coding will show where
each metadata identifier is
displayed.
So, this is where the artwork
will be displayed, the title,
the creation date, and the
description.
And here's a similar screenshot
of the TV Remote app.
You can see here the Remote app
doesn't display exactly the same
set of metadata as
AVPlayerViewController.
It displays the same artwork and
title, but instead of displaying
the description it instead
displays the artist and the
album name.
You can see the AV foundation
identifiers to use here.
Okay that's all for AVKit.
If you're just playing your
video using some other
technology like Video Toolbox or
if you're playing audio only
content then you'll need another
way to provide Now Playing info.
In those cases, you can use the
MPNowPlayingInfoCenter.
This is a singleton object that
has a dictionary property that
you can write your metadata
into.
So, there's a key for title, for
album name, for artwork and so
on.
In addition to the metadata that
you are probably expecting you
can also specify explicitly if
the content is audio or video.
You can also provide some
information about the content
duration and the user's current
playback position.
Your artwork is not provided as
raw bytes, but as an
MPMediaItemArtwork object which
we'll talk about more in just a
minute.
Finally, it's your
responsibility to update this
metadata dictionary as the
playback state changes.
You do not need to update it
every second or even every
minute, but you should update it
when certain events occur.
We recommend that you update it
when the currently playing item
changes, if any metadata about
the currently playing item
changes, such as the title or
artist name, if the user seeks
to a new position of the content
or if the playback rate changes
and finally, if playback begins
or stops.
Let's take a look at some code.
Here in the first code block,
I'm creating the object that's
going to represent my artwork.
The way this MPMediaItemArtwork
class works is that you provide
us with the native size of the
image in a block that we'll call
later with specific image sizes.
The way this MPMediaItemArtwork
class works is that you provide
us with a native size of the
image in a block that we'll call
later with specific image sizes.
This block should return a
UIImage object that closely fits
inside the size that's passed to
the block.
So, for example, your app may
have downloaded several
different sizes of the same
artwork say in small, medium and
large sizes.
When we call this block, you
should take the size we provide
and return the image that most
closely fits the requested size.
We would discourage you from
trying to perform expensive
image resizing operations here,
just return the image that you
already have.
In the second block of code,
this is where I'm actually
providing all of my metadata to
MPNowPlayingInfoCenter.
You can see that this is just a
plain Swift dictionary with some
keys that are provided by the
framework and I'm simply
providing my values as regular
Swift types.
There are two properties that I
want to call out in particular
though.
The ElapsedPlaybackTime and the
PlaybackDuration.
Like I mentioned earlier, you
should provide these keys so
that tvOS knows how long your
content is and where the user is
currently at within the content.
As various playback events occur
you should update the
ElapsedPlaybackTime to match
where the user currently is.
There's no
AVPlayerViewController for this
API on tvOS, but I can show you
what this metadata looks like in
the TV Remote app.
You can see where each property
is displayed onscreen.
These should look pretty
familiar compared to the AVKit
version.
Take note that in this version
though the scrubber bar is under
your control.
The ElapsedPlaybackTime and the
duration need to be provided by
your app to be displayed
correctly here.
All right, let's change gears a
bit now and talk about how your
app can handle external playback
commands.
Of course, your app will have
its own controls that the user
can interact with when your app
is displayed, but the user may
also want to control your app
from the TV Remote app on iOS or
if they're listening to
background audio from your app
on tvOS pressing the play pause
button on the Siri remote can
pause your app even while it's
in the background.
To support these kinds of
interactions you will need to
make sure your app can handle
these Remote Commands.
The way to do that is with an
API called
MPRemoteCommandCenter.
The way to do that is with an
API called
MPRemoteCommandCenter.
This is another singleton object
that has a property for each
different kind of command that
your app can choose to support.
For each command that you want
support you can register either
a target-action pair or a
callback block which will be
invoked when the command is
performed.
If you provide a target-action
or a block the command is
assumed to be supported.
If you want to provide a handler
for the command, but need to
temporarily indicate that it's
not available you can mark it as
disabled.
The method or block that you
provide must return an enum
value to indicate if your app
was able to successfully perform
the command.
The definition of success here
is pretty broad.
For example, if the user is
playing the last song in a
playlist and requests to skip to
the next track your app may
choose to simply end playback.
That would still be considered
successfully handling the
command so you should return the
success value in that case.
Some commands like play and
pause are pretty simple.
If the handler for the pause
command is invoked it's pretty
clear what your app needs to do.
But other commands are more
flexible and both accept
parameters from your app and can
provide more parameters back to
your handler.
For example, the
MPSkipIntervalCommand is used to
allow the user to skip forward
or backward by several seconds.
Your app can express a
preference for how many seconds
the user should be allowed to
skip.
The skip command object allows
you to configure that
preference.
When the user actually performs
the skip command your handler
will be invoked with an object
parameter.
That object is of the type
MPSkipIntervalCommandEvent and
it has an interval property that
tells your app how many seconds
you should skip.
And be careful this may not be
the same as the skip preference
you provided earlier.
Let's look at an example.
Here's how an app might
implement the skip backward
command.
You can see here that on the
first line I would prefer that
the user skips backward by 10
second intervals so I'm going to
assign the preferred intervals
property on the
SkipBackwardCommand object.
Then I'm going to provide my
handler block.
Now technically every command
handler receives the generic
type MPRemoteCommandEvent as the
parameter, but I need to cast it
to an MPSkipIntervalCommandEvent
so that I can get to its
interval property.
Then I'm going to actually
perform the command.
In this sample, I'm playing my
content with an AVPlayer.
Since AVPlayer expresses its
time using CMTime structs that's
how I'm going to need to
calculate my new playback
position.
You can see here that I'm
getting the player's current
composition then creating a new
CMTime struct with the skip
interval.
Finally, I'm subtracting that
interval from the current time.
I ask the player to seek to that
time and then return successful
from the command handler.
When the player finishes seeking
to the new time my completion
handler will be invoked and
that's where I'm going to update
my Now Playing info.
Remember, if we modify playback
state like seeking to a new time
we need to publish new Now
Playing info so we can update
the elapsed playback time.
Here I'm calling a function
called updateNowPlaying which
I'll show you on this next
slide.
Here you can see how I'm going
to update my Now Playing info.
This is basically the same as
the example I showed you at the
beginning of this section, but
want to call out one specific
detail.
Here you can see that I'm using
the AVPlayer's current time
property in order to provide an
accurate value for the elapsed
playback time property.
In this case, since AVPlayer is
going to return a CMTime, but
MPNowPlayingInfoCenter requires
a floating-point value, that's
the number of elapsed seconds, I
need to use the CMTimeGetSeconds
function to convert the value.
And that's all there is to
providing a great playback
experience with Remote Commands
and Now Playing information.
For more information, you can
visit the URL shown here to find
links to documentation and
related sessions.
Thanks for watching.