[ Applause ]
>> Good afternoon.
Thank you, it's good to be here.
We have some very great stuff
for you today.
Last year we unveiled automatic
signing and it's great.
Automatic signing was a major
leap forward in the ease-of-use
for how you sign your app.
Today we're taking the next
step, we're making it possible
to use automatic signing for
distribution, Xcode Build, and
Xcode Server.
So, what exactly are we going to
talk about today?
The first thing is I'm going to
very briefly review the
fundamentals of signing and how
it works on our platforms.
Next, I'm going to show you how
to set up Xcode Server to
perform development signing so
that you can regularly run tests
on the device.
Then I'm going to show you some
of the great changes that we've
been making to manual signing.
Itai is going to come up and
show you all of the great
changes we've been making to
distribution and distribution
signing.
And Brent will come up to show
you how to set up Xcode Server
and for the first time perform
distribution signing.
So, before we get in too deep I
would like to take a moment to
remind us why we do this, why do
we code sign.
Well the simple answer is that
code signing protects us, it
protects us as users, it
protects us as developers, and
all of us are users, all of us
download apps from the store and
we're sure that that app came
from the developer that wrote it
because of code signing.
And every app that we download
from the Store we're sure that
Apple has approved that that app
is allowed to use special system
services.
We can trust the security and
the privacy of our devices
because of code signing.
So how does this actually work?
Well every app has a code
signature and when the app is
run the system checks for a
couple things, it first checks
that that signature is valid,
that it hasn't been tampered
with since it came from the
original developer.
And that that app is allowed to
use special system services like
app groups.
And the signature also tells us
if it's been provisioned for
this device, if it's for
development it's been
provisioned for a couple
devices, and if it's for the App
Store that code signature says
it can run on any device.
Now composing this signature
Xcode uses three essential
ingredients, our good friends
the signing certificate, a
provisioning profile, and
entitlements.
Now I'm going to spare you a
very detailed explanation of how
all of this works, but I would
like to refer you to last year's
talk, what's new in Xcode app
signing where we go into great
detail about how this works with
our platforms and how it works
with Xcode 8.
What I will say is that
collecting all of these assets
it's not that much fun, it's
complex which is why in Xcode 8
we introduced a solution to
manage all of this complexity,
automatic signing.
When you enable automatically
managed signing Xcode will
automatically create app IDs, it
will create certificates, it
will update provisioning
profiles, it will update
entitlements, it will do all of
that stuff you don't want to
deal with so that you can get on
with your development.
Enabling automatic signing is
really the way to go.
And I'm pleased to announce that
in Xcode 9 all of this great
functionality is available in
Xcode Server.
And we know that there are
certain situations in which
you'd like to directly
manipulate your signing
configuration so we also have
manual signing support in Xcode
Server.
So, for those of you who don't
know I hope you know that Xcode
Server is the continuous
integration service powered by
Xcode and now it is built right
into Xcode.
You no longer need to have
Server App installed.
If you've used this before this
is a huge convenience, it has
never been easier to get going
with continuous integration.
And Xcode Server allows you to
very easily set up testing on
the simulator and on the device.
Now testing on the device
requires code signing, so I'd
like to explain how code signing
fits into the greater picture of
Xcode Server.
When you're working on your app
in Xcode you work on a project
and you upload updates to that
project to a remote repository.
You then set up Xcode Server
with a bot to pull from that
repository, build your app and
run tests on the device.
And running on a device requires
a code signature and Xcode
composes that code signature
using those essential
ingredients, the provisioning
profile and a signing
certificate.
So, how are we going to get
those onto Xcode Server?
Well the good news is if you
have targets enabled with
automatic signing this can just
happen for you.
Xcode Server will automatically
create certificates, it will
update provisioning profiles, it
will register devices all so
that signing can be performed.
This is really fantastic.
And if you have manual setup for
your targets Xcode Server now
has UI for you to send any
certificates from your
administrative Mac over to the
server that will be performing
integrations in code signing.
So, Xcode Server now has support
for automatic and manual
signing.
Now Xcode Server is able to make
use of automatic signing because
you join Xcode Server to your
team as another member, you do
this during Xcode Server setup
if you're a team agent or admin.
And Xcode Server now supports
logins from Apple IDs with two
factor authentication.
Now all of this great signing
functionality is available to
Xcode Server because Xcode
Server under the hood calls out
to the command line tool
Xcodebuild, which means that
Xcode Build now offers command
line support for automatic
signing repairs and this is
huge.
Now if you have a third-party
continuous integration service
you should listen up because
what this means is that
Xcodebuild can now update
provisioning profiles, it can
download them, it can create
certificates, all that magic
that happens in the UI can now
happen on the command line.
[ Applause ]
And you enable this in
Xcodebuild by passing the flag
allowProvisioningUpdates.
And we've added some extra
automation, if you have a device
connected to your Mac you can
have it automatically registered
with your team without
interaction if you also pass the
flag allowProvisioning
DeviceRegistration so very cool.
So, as I've said, setting up
Xcode Server is super easy now
that it's built right into Xcode
9.
I'd like to show you how you set
up Xcode Server briefly so that
I can show you how to set up
signing for that server.
So, the first step is opening up
the preferences of Xcode and all
the way to the right we have a
new tab Server and Bots, that's
where you turn on Xcode Server.
The next step is opening up the
accounts pane where you can add
a client account that way you
can view your server working.
The next step is opening up your
project and using the product
menu to create a bot.
And then in the reports
navigator you can view all the
integrations that your bot has
been running, you can see all
the servers and bots and on each
integration you can see whether
your project has built, whether
tests you have have run and
whether they've succeeded or
failed that's what you can see
here.
And now when you set up Xcode
Server there's a new tab, the
signing tab, this is what it
looks like.
This gives a number of options
so that you can set up Xcode
Server to be powered to use
automatic signing.
This first checkbox, allow Xcode
Server to manage my certificates
and profile, will give Xcode
Server the power to use
automatic signing for any of
those targets in which it's
enabled.
And you authorize that again by
adding Xcode Server to your team
and to do that here.
And then there's this other
checkbox, automatically add
missing devices to my developer
team, this will automatically
register any devices connected
to your Mac without interaction.
And those two checkboxes in the
UI mirror those flags,
allowProvisioningUpdates and
allowProvisioning
DeviceRegistration for up
Xcodebuild.
So, I've said enough why don't I
actually show you this working.
Okay, so I have opened up Xcode
to my project chocolate chip and
I have already set up server
with a bot to perform
integrations on the simulator.
So, I've just purchased this
shiny new device and I'd like to
run tests on the device.
In order to do that I need to
enable Xcode Server to make use
of automatic signing.
So, first step is clicking on
the reports navigator and you
can see here the server that
I've created, the bot, and the
one integration that's run.
And I'm going to control
Control-click and bring up the
bot editor.
So, my first step will be
clicking on the devices tab
where you can see that I've set
up Xcode Server to run tests on
the iPhone SE simulator, I'm
going to change that instead to
run on any device that's
connected to this Mac.
Next, in the signing tab you can
see what we've been talking
about.
I'm going to allow Xcode Server
to create certificates and
profiles, I'm going to add Xcode
Server to my team, and I'm going
to allow Xcode Server to
automatically register any
device that's connected,
including this one.
All right, so we're all ready to
get started testing on the
device.
I'm going to manually initiate
an integration.
So, what's happening now is
Xcode Server is downloading the
project from the repository,
it's building the app, it's
creating a certificate,
registering my device, adding
that device to the profile,
downloading the profile, and
signing it also so that we can
run tests on the device.
And normally I would say don't
watch your bot it's not that
much fun, you can let this
automate itself in another room,
but after a certain amount of
bake time our cookies will be
done.
And there we go, all two of my
tests have passed, I'm in very
good shape.
So, you've just seen how you can
set up Xcode Server to
automatically perform
development signing so that you
can run tests on the device.
Now we really like automatic
signing, we don't want you to be
consumed with managing all of
these assets, we want to be
coding, we want you to be coding
as well.
Setting automatic signing I do
it, we suggest everyone do it.
However, we know that there are
certain situations in which you
may want to directly manipulate
your signing configuration and
for that we have manual signing
and now we've improved it.
We've added some improvements to
the certificate sheet in the
accounts preferences.
Now this sheet will tell you
what certificates you've created
on your Mac and other Macs that
you own.
That's the developer
certificates above and in the
section below you can see all of
the distribution certificates
that have been created by anyone
on your team, whether they're on
your machine or not.
And we've improved the
visibility here, now you can see
when a certificate is missing a
private key or it's been revoked
and we even include the creator
of the certificate and you can
email the creator of that
certificate right from the sheet
and asked them to share it with
you.
[ Applause ]
In the project editor when
you're using manual you select
the profile yourself and we've
added a new menu item download
profile it'll bring up a sheet
that looks like this.
And you can see on the left a
list of eligible profiles from
profiles that I've created on
the portal and these are
profiles that are eligible for
my target.
When I've selected one you can
see a detailed view of that
profile and see how it compares
with your target, whether the
capabilities match, even if the
device is connected you can see
if that device is in the
profile.
This is a major improvement for
finding the right profile before
you select it and try to sign
with it.
And if you have a profile
selected already, but it's not
installed locally on your
machine Xcode will offer to
download that profile for you if
we know it will work.
Now we know that you're still in
manual, we're not interested in
touching your project state or
your portal state, we're very
clear about this distinction,
this is really just a
convenience.
And of course, in Xcode Server
we also have manual support.
Under the signing tab you'll see
a tab that's like this, the
certificates and profiles tab,
where you can see a list of the
certificates and profiles
installed on your local machine
that you can send over to your
server to perform manual
signing.
So, when you are using manual
signing we recommend using the
general tab to make any changes
to your signing setup.
However, if you have automation
or at you just don't want to use
the UI, we have build settings
for extra flexibility.
In Xcode 8 we introduced
Development Team that's to set
the team identifier.
Provisioning Profile Specifier
to set the profile by name.
And Code Sign Identity to set
the certificate.
And in Xcode 9 we're introducing
a new build setting Code Sign
Style.
You can use Code Sign Style to
set the style to automatic or
manual at the target or build
configuration level.
We think that this is exciting,
but it's for advanced use cases.
For most cases, you should be
able to set your entire target,
keep it set to automatic.
Well you've seen just about all
there is for development
signing.
We've made a lot of great
improvements to distribution and
distribution signing.
For more on that please give a
warm welcome to my friend, Itai
Rom.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you Chris, good
afternoon everyone.
So, Chris just showed you all
the improvements we've made when
your development signing your
app.
I'd like to change gears a bit
and talk about distribution.
Now when you're ready to share
your app with others the first
thing you need to do is build an
archive.
An archive is a special release
build of your application and we
recommend development signing
it.
In fact, that's the default
setting.
Now the reason that we recommend
that this is so that any
developer on your team can
easily build an archive and
share it with others without
needing access to any special
distribution signing
certificates.
The archive contains both the
machine code and bitcode of your
app, as well as your debugging
symbols all bundled up together.
And once you've built one of
these you can use Xcode's
organizer window to generate an
IPA and upload it to the App
Store.
When you generate that IPA Xcode
will distribution sign your app
according to App Store
requirements.
So, this is the other part of
why you can develop sign your
archives because Xcode will
resign your app when you
distribute it.
In fact, you can distribute your
archive in a variety of ways.
You can ad hoc distribution sign
it if you want to share the app
with other people on your team
or your QA engineers or if
you're a member of the
Enterprise Developer Program you
can enterprise sign it and share
the app with other employees in
your company.
Now, in addition to the
distribution method there are a
lot of other choices you need to
make when you distribute your
app.
You need to choose how you want
to sign it, which profiles to
use, which entitlements it
needs.
If you're using bitcode, app
thinning or on demand resources
then you also need to decide how
you want to handle those
features.
And if you're uploading to the
App Store then you need to
decide whether you want to
include symbols or not.
So, this can get quite complex.
I'm pleased to announce that in
Xcode 9 we've made some major
improvements to the distribution
workflow that will make it
easier than ever before to share
your apps with others while also
giving you more power and
control over the process.
Now the first thing we've added
is automatic signing.
This works just like during
development, so Xcode will take
care of all the distribution
signing details for you and you
can focus on other tasks.
In addition to automatic signing
for those of you who want full
control we've added manual
signing to the distribution
workflow.
So now you can create your own
distribution profiles and tell
Xcode which ones to use, but
Xcode will never create or
modify any of those profiles.
In addition to automatic and
manual resigning we've made a
lot of other improvements.
We've streamlined the
distribution workflow.
So, for example Xcode won't ask
you which Development Team you
want to use anymore because it
already knows the answer.
[ Applause ]
We've also improved the
visibility of errors, so now
it's easier to tell what went
wrong when you run into a
problem and what you need to do
to resolve it.
We've enhanced export
functionality, so now in Xcode 9
once you've uploaded your app to
the App Store you can save a
copy of your IPA in case you
need to refer back to it later
on.
And finally, we've enhanced the
command line support in
Xcodebuild so that you can take
advantage of all these new
features in your automation.
Let's dive into automatic
signing a little bit more.
This works just like development
signing, Xcode will create
Xcode-managed distribution
profiles.
These are profiles that are
completely under Xcode's control
and they're the only profiles
that Xcode will use for
automatic distribution signing.
It will never touch or use any
of your manually made profiles.
In addition, Xcode will make it
easy to create and share your
distribution certificates.
These are different from
development certificates because
their team owned signing assets.
So, it's really important that
you know when you've created one
and you save it so that you can
reinstall it later or share it
with others.
And finally, last but not least,
for those of you with carefully
crafted signing setups in Xcode
9 Xcode will never offer to
revoke a distribution
certificate.
[ Applause ]
Yes, we're all very happy about
that one.
So, you don't have to worry
about any enterprising member of
your team ruining your carefully
crafted setup through Xcode
anymore.
So, here's an example of
improved error presentation.
This is a common and potentially
confusing situation, someone on
your team has already created
the distribution certificate,
but you don't have that
certificate or more likely you
don't have its private key.
Well now Xcode 9 tells you
exactly who created those
certificates, makes it really
easy to contact them so you can
get the information you need to
finish the workflow.
Now that's just one example,
there are many others throughout
the distribution workflow of
improved errors.
The enhanced export
functionality.
So, as I mentioned earlier, now
it's easy to save aside a copy
of your IPA after you've
uploaded it to the App Store,
but you get more than that.
We also give you a
DistributionSummary.plist so
just like a receipt, it shows
you all the content in your IPA,
how Xcode resigned it, which
entitlements it has and so on.
You also get a Packaging.log
which is like a Build.log, it
shows you step-by-step all the
commands that Xcode issued when
it transformed your archive into
an IPA and you get an
ExportOptions.plist.
So, this last one is kind of
interesting.
An ExportOptions.plist is like a
recipe, it describes how you
want to transform your archive
into an IPA.
And when you want to automate
the process of generating IPAs
what you do is you invoke
Xcodebuild and give it one of
these ExportOptions.plists.
Now in Xcode 9 it's really easy
to create these because the
distribution workflow will
generate one for you so you
don't need to manually edit
these plists anymore.
Here's an example of what one
looks like.
This is a really simple
ExportOptions.plist, as you can
see I've set up automatic
signing and I'm exporting for
the App Store.
And this last key in their
upload symbols I actually don't
even need to include that
because it defaults to yes.
Now there are a lot of options
that you can specify in these
files, you can invoke
Xcodebuild-help in terminal to
see everything that you can
include in an
ExportOptions.plist.
But most of the options have
sensible defaults.
When you're ready to use this,
all you do is invoke
Xcodebuild-exportArchive, pass
the path to your archive and the
path to your ExportOptions.plist
and Xcodebuild will generate an
IPA for you.
Now there's one other thing, as
you'll recall from Chris'
section, we've added a new flag
to Xcodebuild called
allowProvisioningUpdates and you
can use that here as well, so
that Xcodebuild will
automatically generate
distribution provisioning
profiles for you.
Anything that's necessary in
order to generate your IPA.
So, let's take a look at the new
distribution workflow in action.
Okay, so here's our chocolate
chip app which we've been
working on for a while and as
you can see, our extensive
two-test suite is passing so now
we're ready to upload it to the
App Store.
I'm going to start that off by
clicking product and creating an
archive.
And Xcode is going to do that
release build on my app, bundle
it all up and then show me the
archive once it's completed in
the organizer window.
From here I can easily upload it
to the App Store by clicking
this very shiny enticing blue
button.
And when I click that the
distribution workflow will drop
down.
Now Xcode is going to start by
analyzing some of the content in
my archive and that includes how
my app was signed, so that's how
Xcode knows which Development
Team I'm using it just reads the
signature of my archived app.
It also determines which options
to show me on the next screen.
This content is going to vary
depending on what's in your
archive, as well as the
distribution method you choose.
So, if I had chosen ad hoc
distribution then I'd see some
different options in here.
So, in this case I have a
bitcode option because my app
contains bitcode, I also have a
new Strip Swift Symbols option.
What this is going to do is it
allows the App Store to strip
Swift symbols from the Swift
standard libraries in my app and
that's going to greatly reduce
the download size of my app for
my customers, so I'm going to
leave that on.
I also have the option to upload
symbols which will allow me to
receive symbolicated crash
reports from Apple, so I'll
leave that on as well and click
Next.
The next step is where I can
choose how I want to resign my
app.
I'll talk a little bit more
about manual signing later for
now, we'll stick to automatic.
And Xcode is going to start
talking to the developer website
and figuring out how to resign
my app.
The first thing it looks for is
a distribution signing
certificate.
Now in this case, my team hasn't
actually created one yet, so
Xcode tells me about that and
asks me if I want to create one.
So now Xcode won't just create
one behind my back I'm fully
aware that I'll have a
distribution certificate and all
I need to do is give Xcode
permission and click Next and
Xcode will generate it.
After that Xcode will ask me if
I want to export my certificate.
Like I said earlier, this is
really important because these
are team owned assets and there
might be other people on my team
who need to also distribution
sign or I might need to
reinstall the certificate later,
so we really recommend exporting
a copy of your certificate.
For now, since this is a demo
I'll click Next.
And now Xcode is going to
continue talking to the portal
generating my distribution
provisioning profiles, I'll
allow code sign to use my newly
created signing certificate
that's how you can tell this is
live.
And once Xcode is done it'll
show me details about the IPA
that it's created.
I can see all the content in my
IPA including my framework, my
app extension, and my launch app
right in here.
I can see how they're signed and
I can double-check that the
entitlements are correct.
So, this gives me a chance to
make sure my app is all correct
before I upload it to the App
Store.
Once I'm sure it looks fine I'll
click Upload and Xcode will
upload my app to the Store.
Now in the past once this
completes this is where the
workflow would end in Xcode, but
now there's one additional thing
I can do here, I can export.
So, when I select Export and
save to the desktop Xcode will
generate a new directory
containing my IPA, as well as
all of those other files,
including an ExportOptions.plist
that I mentioned earlier.
So that's the new distribution
workflow using automatic signing
in Xcode 9.
Now let's talk a little bit
about manual signing.
Manual signing also works just
like during development.
You or someone on your team will
create provisioning profiles and
then you can select them in the
Xcode distribution workflow.
Xcode won't ever create or
modify any of these manual
profiles so you're in full
control.
This is fully compatible with
Xcodebuild so you can still
automate the creation of your
IPAs if you want use manual
signing.
But there's one note, if your
archive was manually signed when
you built it then you also need
to manually sign when you
distribute.
So, how do you use manual
signing?
You'll recall this screen for my
demo moment ago, if you choose
manual signing click Next, then
you'll be greeted with this
interface.
This is really similar to the
signing UI that you see in the
general tab in Xcode's project
editor.
You can select the distribution
certificate you want to use and
then profiles for each of the
items in your app.
When you pop open those pop-up
menus you see the profiles that
are eligible, ineligible, you
can import profiles or download
profiles from the portal
directly within the distribution
workflow.
And if you select an ineligible
profile you'll see issues
associated with that selection
right underneath your selection.
Once you've selected valid
profiles for everything in your
app you can click Next and
continue with the workflow.
And as I said, this is all fully
compatible with Xcodebuild all
you need to do is specify a
couple of additional keys in
your ExportOptions.plist.
So, you can see here I set
signing style to manual and I've
also provided a provisioning
profiles entry that lists all
the items in my app by bundle
identifier and all the profiles
I want to use.
And that's it now I'm set up for
automation.
So that's the new distribution
workflow in Xcode 9, we think
you're all really going to love
it.
And now I'd like to invite Brent
on stage to talk about
distribution signing in Xcode
Server.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you everyone, I'm
really excited to be here today
because for the first time in
public we're going to show you
how you can use in Xcode Server
to automatically create
distribution signed IPAs for
you.
This is really exciting, it's a
missing piece of the puzzle, and
we finally delivered it and it's
really great.
But first, how did we do this?
Well in Xcode 8 and Xcode 9 we
introduced great automatic
signing workflows in Xcode and
Xcode Server gets all of that
for free.
Likewise, all of the
distribution workflows and the
underlying technology Xcode
Server also gets that from
Xcode.
So, we have automatic signing,
we have distribution, we have
Xcode Server, we have great
workflows for development and
distribution signing.
How does this all work?
So, Chris showed a slide that
looked a little bit like this
and it's important to understand
how Xcode Server does this job.
In order to create -- in order
to sign an archive to create an
IPA from it for distribution
Xcode Server needs some special
assets just like for
development, it needs signing
certificates and it needs
provisioning profiles.
Now fortunately, we've made this
very easy.
If you allow Xcode Server to
communicate with the developer
portal on your behalf it can get
most of these things for you.
It can get the provisioning
profiles automatically.
But there's one thing it can't
get and that's the distribution
signing certificate.
That's really no big deal
because we've provided a great
experience for you to share this
with your server.
So, once your Xcode server has
all of these assets it can build
an archive and then it can
transform that archive into an
IPA for distribution to the App
Store.
So, what do you need to do?
You need to copy distribution
certificates to the server, you
need to make sure that automatic
signing is turned on so this
will also work for manual and
I'll show you that.
And then thirdly, there's this
ExportOptions.plist that Itai
talked to you about, so what's
that all about.
Well the ExportOptions.plist is
just a simple recipe for how you
want Xcode Server to transform
your archive into an IPA.
That can be very simple and it
can also scale up to some more
complex manual signing scenarios
too.
So, I've been saying App Store a
lot, but I want to emphasize
that what we've built here lets
you distribute for all the
distribution methods, so if
you're doing enterprise or ad
hoc or App Store or whatever
this will just work, so we think
that's really great.
So, let's see this in action.
So, here's our chocolate chip
bot that's been dutifully
building our app and running
tests on devices for a few
months now.
So, what I want to do is I want
to repurpose this bot to build
IPAs for me.
Now we recommend as a best
practice that you create a
dedicated bot for this purpose
for creating IPAs, but I'm just
going to repurpose this one for
demo purposes today.
So, we'll go and edit the bot.
There are a lot of options in
the bot editor, but what we need
to do today is pretty simple.
First, we're going to visit the
configuration tab and in here
we're going to turn on
archiving.
Remember since Xcode 5 when we
introduced Xcode Server it's
been able to create archives for
you and there have been a lot of
great workflows there.
For example, you can create
archives and then do over the
air installs with Xcode Server
and that's been great.
You can still do that.
But there's one new option that
we've added here and that's what
enables Xcode Server to create
this distribution signed IPA for
you.
So, that's the final option
here, use custom
ExportOptions.plist, well where
do I get one of those?
Itai being the great guy that he
is you may remember he exported
that for me after he upload his
app to the App Store.
So, I'll go and I'll select that
now.
So, it's a good idea at this
point that you verify that this
is the right ExportOptions.plist
so conveniently you can just
click it.
This is a pretty simple example
of an ExportOptions.plist, but
you may remember from one of
Itai's slides if you're doing --
if you some more complex manual
workflows you would end up
perhaps having specific
provisioning profiles here and
other things you can do so
that's a good idea, just verify
that this is the right
ExportOptions.plist.
So, we've done that and that's
it for the configuration tab.
Let's visit the signing tab.
So, this is brand new in Xcode 9
and we're pretty excited because
this is how you configure Xcode
Server to do both development
signing and distribution
signing.
So, these two checkboxes at the
top Chris already checked for us
and remember the top one lets
Xcode Server communicate with
the developer website on my
behalf.
My team is already added to the
server and even if you have a
manual distribution workflow
it's a really good idea that you
still have this checkbox
checked.
So, now let's visit the
certificates and profiles tab,
so what's in here.
There are two tables at the top,
it shows me all the certificates
that are installed on this
machine, at the bottom are the
provisioning profiles.
And what I need to do is I need
to share the distribution
certificate with my server and
that's really easy just click
Add to Server and it's done.
That's all I need to do and now
Xcode Server has access to that
distribution certificate and
because I've allowed it to talk
to the developer website on my
behalf it can get all the assets
it needs to create that IPA.
You may be wondering what I need
to do with the provisioning
profiles table.
Well for most of you if you're
doing automatic code signing and
you're doing App Store
distribution you don't need to
do anything.
But if you're targeting one of
those other distribution methods
or you've specified particular
profiles in that
ExportOptions.plist that we
looked at, you're on the hook
for making sure your server has
those provisioning profiles.
Again, that's really easy, any
profile you want to share you
just click Add to Server and
that will share it with your
Xcode Server.
So that's it, I visited the
signing tab and the
configuration tab.
And now this is the moment
you've been waiting for.
Let's integrate this bot and
watch it create two things, it's
going to create an archive and
then it's going to transform
that archive into a distribution
signed IPA that I can then
upload to the App Store.
And there it is.
So, for the first time we think
this is a really exciting
development in Xcode Server and
it's going to save you a lot of
time.
[ Applause ]
So, code signing, code signing
is really important and we
should feel fortunate as
developers and users that we're
using platforms where code
signing is an integral part of
the experience.
It keeps us safe, it keeps us
secure, we know it's hard to get
right.
But in Xcode 8 and Xcode 9 we've
put a ton of work into providing
really great solutions for you
and we think it's easier than
ever.
So, we have development signing
with Xcode Server for your
day-to-day development and
testing on devices.
We've also done a lot of work
for manual signing because we
know that's important to a lot
of you.
We made big improvements to the
distribution workflow in Xcode
and of course, we've brought
that distribution workflow to
Xcode Server.
So that's it, there are a lot
more related sessions this week
on this topic.
Thanks for attending and have a
great week.