[ Applause ]
>> Good afternoon and welcome to
Localizing Content for Swift
Playgrounds.
I am Alex Kuhn.
I'm an engineer on the Content
team, developing content for
Swift Playgrounds, and I'll be
joined later by Aaltan Ahmad
from the Internationalization
Team.
Now it's a big world out there
full of many different diverse
people that would love to use
the amazing content that you
build in Swift Playgrounds.
However, at Swift Playgrounds,
right now we have over a million
users.
Except nearly two-thirds of them
are outside the US.
So for them to be able to use
your amazing content you need to
localize it to hit this whole
world, is what we'll talk about
today.
So a little bit of history on
Swift Playgrounds.
This is an iPad app that enables
you to write Swift code and see
the results of it executed live.
And along with Swift Playgrounds
we've released a curriculum
teaching a beginner the basics
of learning the code.
And also, there is different
coding challenges such as
writing the logic for the game
of Battleship.
Now this was initially released
in English, but we have since
translated that into five
additional languages.
Spanish. French.
German. Simplified Chinese and
Japanese.
And we have more coming soon.
And in localizing the content,
we had a number of different
challenges and issues that we
had to encounter and work
through in order to have a great
experience for our users.
And so this is what we want to
talk about some of the lessons
learned for you, when you make
your own content.
So today we'll give an overview
of what is content and Swift
Playgrounds and some of the
challenges around it.
And we'll talk through some of
the localization considerations
when you are making your own
content and localizing it.
And lastly, we'll go through
what is the structure of a
localized Playground book so
that you can make your books
localizable today.
Now before we begin talking
about localization, it's
something that's really critical
is to define your content goals.
And this is important because
when you build the content
initially, when it goes to
localization, you need to be
able to tell someone else what
exactly your goals were, and
what do you want the experience
for that user to be like in any
language, since it's not going
to be you necessarily doing all
of the translations.
So to give an example of the
content goals we had and learned
at code.
For one, it was instructional.
We're trying to teach the
beginner the basics of coding in
Swift, assuming no prior
knowledge.
However, we also want it to be
fun and engaging.
It shouldn't be like a dry
textbook, but rather something
the user wants to use and is
engaged with coding and learning
more.
And we chose to target the ages
of 12 and up.
So whether you're 12 or 112,
we'd love for you to have a
great experience using our
content.
Now just to get an overview of
what this translates to and
learn the code, here you see
this page is about learning
about debugging and finding and
fixing bugs.
Something I'm sure many of you
are quite familiar with.
However, to a learner this is
the first time they're being
introduced to the concept.
Now on the right here we have a
live view.
In this case it's a 3D animated
puzzle world where you're trying
to write code to solve different
puzzles and collect gems.
There's also a prose area that
provides instructional content
and the goals on a page and the
tasks a learner needs to
perform.
And then, of course, the coding
area where they can write and
edit Swift code to solve the
puzzle.
So going back to those goals,
one of ours is to be
instructional.
So we are actually defining what
the term "bug" and "debugging"
means to a learner who might
never have experienced this
before.
And this is something that needs
to be kept into mind with
localization which I'll tie back
to later.
And throughout the course of the
curriculum, there are many such
definitions that occur
gradually.
And in the end, there's a whole
glossary of terms that the
learner gets exposed to when
they go through the curriculum
that has gradually built up to,
and this needs to be taken into
account when you localize it.
Now one other feature in the
system is that when the learner
runs their code, the system is
analyzing what the learner has
done and is trying to help
provide corrective feedback.
Trying to give him instruction
of how to improve or fix what
they did.
So here you'll see that animated
character, Byte, failed to
collect the gem.
And the learner tapped on the
hint saying, "Did you notice
that bug?
Byte tried to collect a gem that
wasn't there."
So here we're taking a
conversational tone trying to be
a little bit more fun and
engaging, while at the same time
giving instructional feedback
saying that they need to use
collect gem, the function, when
they're under a particular gem.
So when this page is put into
Chinese, you'll notice that
while the code is in English
everything else is localized.
And we're still teaching these
exact same concepts, but in a
way that is appropriate to the
language.
So they're still learning about
bugs and debugging, but they
need to be able to relate it
back to the code that they're
seeing on the page.
And similarly, those hints -- we
want to maintain that similar
style, but you'll notice that
we're referencing to the collect
gem command in English.
So this is one of the things
that challenges around
localization of dealing with
these various different
technical terms as well as code
in English that we'll talk more
about later.
Now one other feature in Swift
Playgrounds is we use animated
cut scenes to introduce a
concept at high level before the
learner dives into coding.
So in this case, learner is
learning about what an "if
statement" is before they
proceed to use it.
And when this is localized, the
localization has to take into
account how helping the learner
to actually do the task.
So we're still mentioning if
statement -- the if command in
English, even though everything
else is in Chinese because
that's how they're going to need
to solve the puzzles later when
they write Swift Code.
So that's a little overview of
the content.
But I'm just going to step back
a moment and talk about the
process of building localized
content.
And a common approach that many
people might take is that you
define your goals and you build
up the content in one language;
testing and iterating it.
Testing it with your users and
making sure you have a great
experience.
Then you decide you want to
localize it.
So then you send it off to your
translators and localize it and
then you get it back and ship
it.
You're done, right?
Unfortunately, this has many
problems.
You may find when you send it
off to be translated that your
content isn't localizable.
Or that there are different
issues in the translation, and
it's not actually hitting the
goals you're seeking at the same
level as when you first
developed it in one language.
So what is the better approach?
Well, for one, localization is
part of the design process.
You should be thinking about
localization when you are
designing out your content goals
and the initial design of the
product in order to avoid costly
mistakes later that prevent
content from being localized.
And this is no different than
what you should do with
accessibility.
Thinking about it during the
design process instead of
afterwards.
Which is what enables you to
make it a really amazing
product.
So a better way to think about
this diagram, is -- the process
is to define your goals and
design out the content thinking
about localization.
And then when you send it off to
be localized, you make sure that
your translators really
understand your goals and what
your content is, so that they
can translate it appropriately
for each language to
consistently hit those goals.
And this may take several rounds
of iteration when you translate
it.
So during this time it's really
critical to test with actual
users, as they're the ones who
you're trying to serve and they
can tell you if you're doing it
right or wrong or if it's
actually meeting their needs and
understandable.
And of course, during this
process you may find you need to
go back and adapt your original
content due to some issues you
found that prevent it from being
localized fully.
But hopefully because you've
considered this in the
beginning, these changes are
relatively minor.
So this is a much better
approach to taking and thinking
about building localized
content.
Now I'll hand it over to Aaltan
to talk about localization
considerations.
>> Thank you Alex.
So today I'm going to talk to
you about the process that we
went through when we localized
Swift Playgrounds, and some of
the key areas that you should be
thinking about when you are
localizing your own Swift
Playgrounds.
So let's go back to that diagram
that Alex introduced to you and
let's talk first about the
process of actually adapting our
own content and goals while
thinking about localization to
begin with before we even start
the actual process of
translation.
and the important thing to
remember here is that your
content choices affect your
localizability of your
playground.
So, for example, if you have a
storyline running through your
prose, or a particular style of
writing that involves wordplay
or puns, this is something that
is really important to
communicate to the people who
are actually translating your
playground, so that they can
maintain that feeling in their
own languages.
Additionally, there may -- the
concepts that you are trying to
teach may be tied to a
particular language in the first
place.
And so you're going to need to
think about adapting these for
localization.
And we can take the example of
Cipher, which is a playground
that we developed where we try
to teach the learner about coded
messages and encryption through
a very story-like setting where
their place is a detective and
follow clues to solve the
mystery.
So here their adding style is
actually kind of unique where we
really place the reader in the
setting of the storyline.
So here we say, "The library is
warm and quiet.
A welcome relief from the
howling snowstorm outside."
And this will be something that
you want to communicate to
translators so that they can
maintain that same narrative
feel, otherwise that friendly,
playful feeling might get lost.
Another part about Cipher is the
clues.
So we have a clue where often
you can bring one of the coded
messages, the learner is told to
look to N for the answer to the
next challenges.
And we actually call this out in
the prose as well, where we say
the message says, "look to N."
Who or what is N?
And right here you can see that
there's an interesting challenge
with the letter N itself.
Different languages have
different alphabets, and some
languages may not even have the
letter N in their alphabet.
And so this is something you'll
want to consider.
If the letter N is particularly
tied to your challenge or
finding clues or investigating
certain things in the puzzle,
that might be a problem down the
road for localizability.
So you want to give translators
the freedom to take this letter
N and actually adapt it to what
feels most comfortable and
natural for their language.
So in Cipher we actually try to
teach the learner about
encryption.
And we do this through a simple
substitution cipher.
And in a substitution cipher you
take your alphabet and you shift
it by a certain number of
letters to create a new mapping.
And using that mapping you can
take a plain text word like
Cipher and encrypt it so it
can't be deciphered without the
right key.
And This works great in English.
But when you translate your
playground and hand it to
someone who's a Spanish speaker,
probably they're going to end up
typing a letter enye, which was
not in your original alphabet.
And if you hadn't thought about
this beforehand, you're going to
be in a situation where maybe a
learner can't solve the next
step of the puzzle, or decrypt
the particular message because
it doesn't work in their
language.
So really, these are the kinds
of things you want to look out
for when you're planning your
content and your puzzles.
Another strategy you can take
when planning out your content
is to actually make it language
agnostic to begin with.
So if you plan it out in a way
that doesn't -- is not
particularly tied to any
particular language or culture,
you can avoid that problem to
begin with.
And that's exactly what we did
with Learn to Code.
We have a made up character,
Byte, in a made up world, that
is free from any kind of
cultural or linguistic ties.
So the translation and
localization process becomes a
lot easier because this puzzle
is pretty much the same, no
matter what language it's
running in.
Collecting a gem is collecting a
gem.
Whether it's in English or in
Spanish.
So that's another strategy you
can use.
Once you've actually planned out
your goals and your content, and
you feel like you're in a good
place with localization and
you're ready to actually
translate, there are a few key
areas that you should keep in
mind when doing this.
So let's talk about the actual
translation process.
The first important thing to
consider is your audience.
So different languages have
different levels of formality.
In English you are you, no
matter what the context.
We don't make any distinction
between addressing someone using
the word, "you".
However, most languages other
than English actually do make a
distinction here such as German
and French.
You can see in German, in an
informal context you would refer
to someone as du.
And in informal context, you
would refer to someone as Sie.
and same for French.
And an important thing to note
about these languages is that
children's texts here are
actually written in the informal
voice.
And this goes a long way to
creating a kind of informal,
comfortable feeling for the
children.
And if you're targeting your
Swift Playground to a younger
audience as we were, using the
informal voice is going to be a
key piece in making this feel
comfortable to them, and like
something they're already used
to reading with from school.
There's an important distinction
here to be made between the
formal and informal voice.
Because in iOS, for alerts or
other messages we actually use
the formal tone.
This is because it's more
appropriate when your phone or
computer is delivering you a
message in a matter-of-fact way,
to have a formal tone of voice.
And of course this contrasts
with Swift Playgrounds.
So this is an important factor
to consider, depending on the
age you're targeting.
Another part of your audience is
going to be how old they are.
And Japanese gives us a good
example to understand this
distinction between older and
younger readers.
So Japanese uses three different
writing systems, and one of
those writing systems is called
Kan ji.
And Kan ji is a pictographical
alphabet that has thousands of
characters.
And the point here is that
children learn these characters
as they grow older, and a
younger person is going to be
familiar with less Kan ji than
an older person.
And they're going to be familiar
with simpler Kan ji rather than
more complex ones.
So how does this factor into
sort of playgrounds?
let's take the example of the
term, "Code area" which we use
to refer to the code editor
where you can input your Swift.
If you handed this off to a
translator without any prior
explanation, or instructions
about what age you're trying to
target, they might choose a
standard Japanese translation of
this, which sort of roughly
sounds like code sphere or
territory.
However, when you inform them
about these goals and the
younger audience that you're
targeting, a better translation
comes out, which is a place to
write code.
And there's a couple of
important points that I want to
highlight between these two
translations.
The first is the usage of the
word "place" versus "fear" or
"territory".
Place is a very common Kan ji,
and so a younger reader is much
more likely to be able to -- to
be familiar with this -- with
these words.
Additionally, we also chose to
include the verb for, "to
write".
To really make it explicit what
the purpose of this area or
place is.
So that can go a long way in
making your Playgrounds easy to
understand.
Technical terms are another area
where you should pay a lot of
attention when writing and
translating your Swift
Playgrounds.
So these can include computer
science terms, math terms, and
of course, the Swift language
keyword, enums, functions and
other code that you include in
your prose.
And to understand this, let's
look at the example that Alex
mentioned earlier about
introducing debugging.
And in order to introduce
debugging, we have to introduce
the concept of a bug.
And in English, we have a simple
phrase here that says, "A
mistake that keeps your program
from running correctly is called
a bug."
And the highlight here is on the
term bug, because that's what
we're going to take and
translate into our various
languages.
So in French we discovered that
while learning programming in
French, the word bug is actually
left untranslated.
And that is the standard for
learning how to program.
So this is, you know, what feels
most natural and comfortable to
a speaker of French, and what's
most appropriate for the
context.
And so in this case, actually
not translating that word and
leaving it in English was the
most appropriate choice.
However, for a language like
Spanish, using a native term,
"error" was through our research
and understanding, a more
appropriate choice here.
And an interesting fact about
the Spanish translation is that
in parentheses, we actually
point out that in English, the
word "error" is called, "bug".
And this allows the learner to
sort of see that term -- see the
term bug outside a Swift
Playground, perhaps, and
actually be able to relate it
back to what they learned in
Swift Playgrounds.
So that's terms that you
actually have a freedom to
translate.
But what about terms that you
can't translate like code?
Here we have the example of the
function moveForward in the
Japanese version of Swift
Playgrounds.
And we needed to mention this
function in the prose to sort of
explain certain concepts.
And Japanese is an interesting
language because it has a
relatively low tolerance for
English words being introduced
into the language.
So it's important that we call
out the simple explanation for
this function moveForward, or
susumo or move in Japanese, in
parentheses following the
occurrence of the function name.
And this really helps the
learner draw a parallel between
the English term and the
Japanese term so that they can
sort of internalize the meaning
of it.
And another interesting thing
about Japanese is because of
this familiarity with English,
or lack of familiarity with
English, we make it a point to
mention these parenthesized
explanations for function names
and other variables throughout
the entire prose instead of
mentioning them when the term is
introduced and then phasing them
out.
And that's a strategy that
varies per language because
different language are familiar
differently with English.
So it's another important thing
to consider.
Your translators will also have
a lot of editorial freedom when
translating Swift Playgrounds.
So here we are introducing and
learn to code three, the concept
of a quadrant and the fact that
the learner can place different
objects at a different
coordinate in the space.
And to do this, of course we
need to talk about the term
quadrant.
So in English, we introduce the
term quadrant by relating it to
quarters.
And there is a nice alliteration
here, and that makes it a little
bit easier for the term to get
introduced.
However, in Japanese we don't
have the advantage of having
this alliteration.
And so the translator here
adopted a different strategy to
use a simple word for area or
[inaudible] outside parentheses.
And then inside parentheses, use
the more technical; complicated
term or shogan for quadrant.
The English translations there
are for your reference below.
So the translator -- an
important thing to note here is
that the translator didn't stick
verbatim to what was in English.
Which might be the default case
if you didn't give them any
instructions.
They might try to stick very
closely to the English text.
So it's important to let them
know that they have the freedom
to do what is most appropriate
and most comfortable for their
own language.
Additionally, because Swift
Playgrounds prose is written in
a variant of Markdown, they
actually have the freedom to add
extra formatting, bold or
italic, or even extra glossary
links to their particular
language if they deem that to be
appropriate.
So when thinking about technical
terms, it's important to keep in
mind that unfamiliar terms are
confusing, and you should be
aware of that when using them in
your prose.
Different languages have
different levels of comfort with
English.
So what works for one language
will not always work for
another.
And lastly, consistency is
really, really important here.
Especially because we're dealing
with terms that might be from a
foreign language or might be
highly technical.
It's important to maintain a
consistent usage of those terms
throughout your prose so that a
person can get more familiar
with them.
So we looked at a lot of
examples of different
localization strategies and
different localization pitfalls
and Swift Playgrounds, and
there's a few things that I want
you to take away from this.
Firstly, your content goals and
your audience are really going
to influence your localization
here, perhaps even more so than
a standard iOS application.
So it's really important to plan
those out with localization in
mind beforehand.
Different languages have
different language features, and
your translators are going to
need to have the freedom to do
what's most appropriate for
their particular language.
Maintaining a style guide or
some kind of document for your
translation process is going to
be really helpful for you here.
Both in, you know, explaining to
your translators how -- what
your goals are; what your
content goals are and how you
want the translations to sound
and feel, as well as any
language-specific issues that
they may encounter and
strategies they want to -- may
want to develop to maintain
consistency throughout your
translations.
And user testing is really your
friend here.
It might be resource intensive
and difficult to find people
that you are targeting with your
playgrounds, but the effort
really, really pays off here.
Because your users of your
target are the audience are the
only people who can really tell
you how effective your
playground is being at teaching
them these concepts.
So lastly, I'd like to bring you
back to this picture of
localization and kind of the
holistic idea here where your
goals -- your original goals and
the localized content are not
really separate entities that
feedback into each other and
really influence each others
development.
It's really important to keep
this in mind when you're taking
your content from English or
whatever you're -- the language
that you wrote it in is into
translated Playgrounds.
Because localization is so often
overlooked as a part of software
development, you have no idea
how much users really appreciate
a well-localized, well-thought
out product.
And I'm confident that if you
try to follow these guidelines
and stick to what we talked
about here, you'll really be
able to give people an amazing
experience in their native
language.
So with that I'll hand it back
to Alex, and he'll take you
through the process of actually
localizing your Playground book.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you Aaltan.
So now we're going to dive into
some of the technical details to
make your book localizable.
And along with this talk there's
also sample code which you can
explore in detail all of the
things we're talking about
today.
Now, this is a page in "Learn to
Code" that's expanded out to
show off all the different areas
that you have to worry about
when you localize.
So on the right you'll see the
live view, but you can have
strings presented to the user.
In this case the audio controls.
There's also prose providing
instructional text.
The editable code area which is
a text that is displayed to the
user before they begin writing
codes to provide a prompt.
Each page can have a title.
Then also different glossary
terms which have definitions for
the learner to learn more about
if they forgot a term.
And a page can have one or more
hints if you want to provide
help for your learner as they're
going through and learning a
concept.
So these are all the different
parts we'll talk about showing
how to localize and what you
need to do for each of them.
And these come in a few
different types of files for
Playgrounds.
You might use a string in a
stringsdict file as well as an
xml plist.
And the cut scenes are written
in html.
And you may also have localized
assets.
So just do a change in each
image for each language to adapt
it.
Now one other detail before we
begin diving into the details is
understanding the overall
structure of a playground book.
So at a base level here, you see
you have a sources directory and
a private resources directory.
And the thing to note here is
that in the private resources
directory, you'll have an lproj
for each language you're
supporting.
In this example we're doing
English and Spanish, with
English being our development
language.
Then there is one or more
chapters in each book.
And each chapter has one or more
pages.
And this is an example in one of
the pages in a book.
And again, the thing to note
here is that the private
resource directory has those
same lproj's for each language
you are supporting.
So what does this look like for
each of the things?
Well, the strings that you have
in the live view, these you
should use in this localized
string for any time you are
using a string that will be
presented to the user.
And a thing to note here is that
it's not just things that
visually appear in the Live
View, but this also is important
for accessibility.
All of your accessibility labels
should use NSLocalizedString, so
that when someone is using the
accessibility features in
another language, they can get
the proper voiceover in their
language and have a great
experience with your content.
Now once you use
NSLocalizedString you would
extract this into the strings
file with a tool we made called
genstrings.
And there's more information on
the developers site of how to
use this tool and extract it.
And there was also a talk
earlier this week on localizing
with Xcode 9 that goes through a
lot of general best practices
with localizing in Xcode.
Now one key thing to note that
you might do in your playground
is using an image with text.
And it's really critical here to
not hardcode the text into the
image, as this will make it very
difficult to localize, requiring
you to remake the image for each
language.
Instead, you can layer the text
on top of it to enable the
translator just to translate the
strings and take advantage of
all of iOS's layout capabilities
to have a great experience for
the learner.
Now once you have these files,
the string file will get
extracted into the base level
private resources folder in the
project.
And optionally for using a
stringsdict file to dynamically
reference a number, such as how
many lines of code the learner
has written, you would create a
stringsdict file for that as
well in the same directory.
So the next piece is the prose.
And this is rendered in markups
to the form of markdown.
And this enables page level
formatting.
You can do bolding, italics, you
can create glossary terms or
link to another page in the
book.
And because of this, you have
this different markup format
that your translators will need
to be aware of to take advantage
of.
So as Aaltan said, you want to
tell all of your translators to
have editorial freedom to adjust
maybe the bolding or the style
per language.
And so they really need to
understand the format in order
to be able to do so.
And it's also important that
they be aware of what terms
cannot be translated that are
actually part of the format so
that they don't accidentally
introduce errors in the code
when they go to localize it.
now how do you make your prose
localizable?
Well, you start a prose block by
this little opening comment
here, and then you add a
localized key.
In this case we're calling it
firstproseblock as a name for
this key.
This will enable it to be
localized.
And then in your lproj you'll
create a prose.strings file and
put that same key there and then
set the value for whatever the
markup that should be
substituted in for that
language.
And the contents.swift resides
at the base directory for each
page.
But the prose.strings file will
be in the private resources for
each language that you're
supporting.
Next is the editable text field
placeholders.
So these are another strings
file.
And you see here the tap to
tenter code.
So how this is defined in the
initial language is just in a
code comment.
Where you see in the
contents.swift tap to enter
code.
And for this to be localizable,
you'll create an editable
field.strings file using the key
being the initial phrase you
created in your contents.swift.
So again, tap to enter code, but
you put in the appropriate
translation for each other
language you're supporting.
And this is done at the base
directory of the Playground book
in the private resources for the
associated languages.
Next up is a page and chapter
titles.
And so here there is a manifest
plist.strings file that you'll
need to create for each page or
chapter, and in this the app is
looking for the key name to
substitute in the new name for
the localized title for your
book.
And this is put in, again, the
private resources for that
particular page for each
language project.
So next up is the glossary.
And this is changing the format
as it's using XML.
And you'll need to make a copy
for this for each language
you're supporting.
But here is an example of the
English glossary.
And we're looking at what the
command definition is in
English.
So one thing to note here is
that the top level key command
is going to be the same across
every language.
This will be how the [applause]
looks up the glossary definition
and will not change.
Similarly, the page reference
should use a -- be by file
reference and not be page
referencing the title, which can
cause it to break in
localization if you were to
change the title.
And then there are several
different strings that you will
send off to your translator to
localize that you see here.
So if this is put into Spanish,
you then see the -- that overall
everything is the same, except
for those three strings get
localized and will be displayed
appropriately when the user runs
the app in Spanish.
And this glossary is stored at
the base-level private resources
in the project.
So you'd have one in your
English lproj, and then also a
copy that's been translated for
your Spanish project.
Hints follow a similar format as
the glossary in that they are
using XML as well.
But these are done on a per page
level.
And each page can have one or
more hints if desired.
And this is an example of what a
hint file looks like.
And in it are several different
strings that your translators
will need to translate.
And so to -- you would make a
copy of this file and have them
localize these strings, and then
you would get this output.
And this new hintplist, this
goes in the private resources
directory for that page, as they
only apply to that particular
page.
And you'd have both the English
version and the Spanish version.
And so last up are the animated
cut scenes, which are html
files.
And these, your translators will
need to make a copy for each
language and appropriately
localize the strings, as well as
potentially change any of the
concepts or images as needed per
each language.
And when they do this, you will
need to put it in the cut scene
pages private resources
directory.
So here we see the English
version is called
conditionalcode.html.
And the initial html file for
each other language needs to
follow that exact same name.
So for Spanish, even though
it'll have all the localized
terms, the file name should be
conditionalcode.html.
So in summary today, we covered
a lot about localization.
And one thing that's really key
to remember is to define who
your audience is, and be sure to
understand them when you're
going into each different
language and trying to adapt the
content.
Localization is really nuance
and complex.
It requires a lot of research
and testing with actual users,
and understanding what are the
standards for each country or
language or region that you want
to go into.
And one thing to keep in mind of
all this is that localization is
really part of the design
process.
And so you should be thinking
about localization up front if
you want to have an amazing
experience for your users.
And I encourage you all to do
so, and make amazing content
that everyone in the world can
experience.
There's more information on the
developer website, as well as
the sample code that goes along
with this.
And there's some fantastic
related sessions on both
localization as well as using
Swift Playgrounds and teaching
with it.
Thank you.
[ Applause and Cheers ]