>> Hello everybody.
My name is Cas Lemmens.
I'm a designer here at Apple,
and I'm delighted to see that so
many people have showed up to
talk about designing across
platforms.
It's a pretty amazing view from
here.
I wish you could see it.
Alright. At Apple, we're really
proud of the platforms that we
create.
For every platform that we've
created, and for every time we
update a platform, we aim to
improve your day-to-day life,
and hopefully create a
meaningful relationship between
the platform and you.
And that relationship doesn't
have to extend to just one
platform.
The more Apple products you use,
the more you rely on not just
single platforms, but on the
entire ecosystem.
You might start your day with a
run on your Watch.
At work, you might be using a
MacBook or an iMac.
When you head home, you might
look up public transportation on
your phone, or use CarPlay in
the car.
When you're at home, you might
unwind watching a TV show or a
movie on the Apple TV, and at
the end of the day, you might
finish a book on your iPad.
Regardless of the device you're
using, you can rely on Apple's
ecosystem to recognize you, to
understand you, and to help you.
Creating and contributing to
this ecosystem requires a very
deep understanding of every
single platform.
As a designer at Apple, that's a
very familiar challenge.
For every app that Apple
creates, we carefully consider
on which platforms it should
live, and how it should scale
between them.
If you look at the apps that
Apple creates, you might notice
that some of them live on all of
our platforms, like Photos, or
Music.
Others only exist on a few, like
Notes, or Mail, or TV.
Some of our services work really
well if you have more than one
device, like ApplePay.
And, others work only if you
have multiple devices available
at the same time, like FaceTime.
Today we're going to talk about
a process that we use at Apple
that can help you design across
platforms.
The goal is to efficiently, but
purposefully, bring your apps to
more platforms.
We're going to start with
selecting.
We're going to look at the
capabilities and the context of
each platform, and make our
decision based on that
information.
Then, we going to adapt.
We're going to look at all the
features and functionality we
want to bring to our platforms
and manage that.
Then, we conform.
We try to find a balance between
our own brand and the platform
guidelines, and to find our look
and feel on them.
Then, we connect.
We see what happens when you go
from one platform to another,
and how it can make that
experience seamless and
effortless.
And, lastly, if possible, we try
to extend.
We see what can happen when
multiple platforms become
available at the same time.
That's the entire process, and
hopefully, at the end of this
talk, you will have all the
required information and
knowledge that you need to make
your apps work amazing in
Apple's ecosystem.
So, let's dig right in.
Let's start with selecting.
When we talk about selecting, we
really want to answer the
question, "What platform do I go
to?"
Maybe you haven't launched your
app yet, and you're trying to
decide what your first platform
will be.
Or, maybe, you have launched
your app on one or two
platforms, and you're trying to
decide where to go next.
Two words come to mind that are
really important when we talk
about selecting a platform.
Context and capabilities.
Context is the time, the place,
and the environment in which
your platform really comes
alive.
And, capabilities are the unique
functionality that makes the
platform distinct from all the
other ones.
It's really important to
understand context, as when
people switch context, they
often switch platform.
I'll give you an example.
Let's say that you're working
behind a desk at school or in
the office.
That's a very focused and
stationary context that you're
in.
When you then leave that place,
and let's say you go to a bus or
a train to head home, that
becomes a very dynamic and
mobile platform.
And, mobile context, sorry.
That's a very big switch in
context, from being very
stationary and focused to being
very mobile and public.
And, that also explains why
people would switch device.
They go from a MacBook or an
iMac, to maybe a phone or Watch.
And, that's because a phone and
a Watch is better optimized for
that context.
Understanding capabilities is
equally important, as they
really allow you to see what
makes a platform unique, and how
your app can benefit from that
capability.
I'll give you a few examples to
show you what I mean.
Let's start with the iPhone.
Maybe the most familiar platform
amongst all of us here.
If you look at the context of
the iPhone, it's always on, it's
always with you, and therefore
it's mobile.
It's a very personal and private
device.
You wouldn't easily share it
with other people, and it's all
optimized for quite short
engagements.
Often when you use the iPhone,
you maybe use it for a couple of
minutes, not more.
The capabilities support the
context.
Because the phone is always on
and always with you, it's very
environment aware.
It has a gyroscope, an
accelerometer, and all that
information is accessible with
background processes even when
you're not using the iPhone.
Because your phone is personal
and private, it's protected with
Touch ID.
And, to make those short
engagements really easy and fun,
you have a very detailed touch
screen.
The Watch is quite similar.
It's also always on and with
you.
It's also personal and private,
but it's much more instant, and
much more optimized for very
short interactions.
A Watch face, for example, gives
you the right information just
by looking at your Watch.
And, notifications just show you
more just by looking long
enough.
The capabilities, again, support
it, because the Watch is so
personal it can track your
movement, it can track your
heart, even your location.
The haptics can tell you when
you should look at your Watch,
and the Watch faces allow you to
customize the information you
want to see at a glance.
Let's look at the iPad.
The iPad has a very mixed
context.
You can use it both at home and
on the go.
You can do very precise and
focused work on it, or just use
it as a lean back device, for
watching movies, TV shows, or
playing games.
And, all of those are longer
engagements than the phone or
the Watch.
The large screen really supports
the context, because it allows
you to do all that precise and
focused work.
The ambient light sensor allows
you to use the iPad both in the
evening and during the day.
The high-fidelity speakers allow
you to create a very immersive
experience with games and
movies, and you have that same
touch screen as on the phone.
And, if you add a pencil to it,
well then it becomes a very
precise interaction.
Let's look at the MacBook.
The context of the MacBook is
always in a very professional
environment.
You can do very precise and
complex work on a MacBook which
is why it's the preferred
platform to design apps or to
develop them.
It can be used as a shared
device, but it's always personal
as everybody has their own
account.
And, you use the MacBook or the
iMac for very long engagements.
Most of us here would probably
be using a MacBook or an iMac
several hours a day.
Let's look at the capabilities.
To do all that professional
work, it has a very high
performance.
The keyboard and mouse allow you
to do very precise and complex
work.
Multitasking allows you to do
exactly what you want to do, how
you want to do it.
And, multi users allow you to
make the MacBook or the iMac a
shared device, but still very
personal.
And lastly, let's look at the
Apple TV.
The Apple TV is a shared device.
You use it together with your
family or your friends.
It's stationary.
You lock it to your TV and it
doesn't really move from that
location.
And, it's completely optimized
for a lean back experience.
You can Watch movies, TV shows,
or play games.
And, again, all of those are
longer engagements, often 30
minutes, to maybe a few hours.
It works really well with an HD
display to make the content
really come alive.
The remote control is light and
easy, and you can just pass it
around to your friends and
family.
Because it's stationary it's
very home aware, which is why it
works so well with HomeKit, and
it's completely optimized for a
10-foot distance, so you can
really just sit back on the
couch, relax, and enjoy the
show.
So, you see that understanding
the context and the capabilities
of each platform is really
important to help you choose
what platform to go to.
The context is where it comes
alive, and the capabilities is
what makes it unique.
And, the same goes for your app,
so you might want to ask
yourself, in what context does
my app really come alive?
And, what are the capabilities
it requires to do so?
At Apple, we have a simple
exercise we like to do a couple
of times when we're trying to
choose on which platforms an app
should be available on.
And, I'll give you a few
examples to show you what I
mean.
Let's look at Activity.
If you think about the
characteristics of Activity,
well, it has to be mobile.
Activity tracks your data --
tracks your movement the whole
day, so to give you accurate
data, it has to be always on,
always with you, and therefore,
mobile.
It also has to be personal.
It should be able to track your
data and only your data.
So, when you look at these two
characteristics, what we do, is
we map them out.
We try to put them on a scale.
For example, if we look at
mobile, we can map that out on a
scale from mobile to stationary.
If you look all of your
platforms on this scale, they
would lay out like this.
The Watch is the most mobile
platform we have, the TV as we
said before, is the most
stationary.
If you look at the other
characteristic, personal, we can
map it out on a scale from
personal to shared, and we get
something like this.
The Watch is the most personal
and mobile platform we have.
The TV is the most stationary
and shared.
When we looked at Activity, we
said, well it had to be
personal, and it had to be
mobile.
So on this chart, it's probably
located somewhere here.
And, that explains why Activity
is available on these platforms,
and not on any other.
I'll show you another example,
let's look at GarageBand.
The characteristics of
GarageBand is that you have to
be able to be really precise.
You want to be able to
manipulate sound exactly where
and when you want it.
And, secondly, it has to work
with multitasking.
You need to be able to play
multiple sounds at the same time
and it needs to be able to
handle all the hardware and
instruments that you might
attach to the platform.
So, again, we can map this out.
Let's look at precise.
We can map that out on a scale
from loose interactions to
precise interactions.
The platforms lay out like this.
On a MacBook with a keyboard and
a mouse, you can be really
precise, but on a Watch, it's a
very small screen and as
everybody has fat fingers, you
might not be able to be that
precise.
If you look at the other scale
of multitasking, we can map that
out on the scale from
multitasking to a single task.
On a MacBook, you can easily do
multiple tasks at the same time.
On a Watch, you can only do one
single task at a time.
If you look at GarageBand to be
set, it had to support
multitasking and it had to be
very precise, so it's located
somewhere here, and that
explains why it's available on
these three platforms, and not
on any other.
This is just a very simple
example, two simple examples
actually of using these
characteristics to choose your
platform.
We do this exercise over and
over again with tons of
characteristics, and in the end,
we hope that we can find a few
platforms on which your app can
really come alive.
And that's exactly what
selecting is all about.
It is choosing a platform based
on the context it supports, and
the capabilities it provides,
and it's validating where your
app can benefit the most.
So, that was step one.
We looked at what platform we
wanted to go to.
Now, we're going to go and look
at adapting.
With adapting, we're going to
look at all the interactions,
all the features, all the
functionality we want to bring
to our app, and try to manage
that across the platforms that
we want to be available on.
I'll explain, again with an
example.
Let's look at Activity on the
iPhone.
Activity on the iPhone, you can
do a whole range of features.
You can look at your progress of
today, you can look at your
achievements, your workouts, you
can see how your friends are
doing.
And, you can manage all that
data.
You can add workouts, you can
invite friends, you can share
the achievements, you can share
progress.
All of that is possible on the
iPhone, and that works well if
you think back about the context
of the iPhone.
The iPhone was a very personal
device, and all these
interactions that you're doing
is with personal information,
and the iPhone was optimized for
quite short engagements.
And, all of these interactions,
they don't take very long.
You can do them relatively
quickly.
But, if you look at how that
scales to the Watch, we see that
actually the feature set is
greatly reduced.
And, again, this makes sense if
you think back about the context
of the Watch.
The Watch is still a very
personal device, and all these
interactions, all this
information is still very
personal, but as we said, the
Watch is optimized for really
short interactions, glances
almost.
So, we made sure that you can
look at your own progress at a
glance, and you can see how your
friends are doing at a glance.
So, one really big part about
adapting is seeing how you
manage your interactions, your
functionality across all the
platforms that you want to be
available on.
Another part, is looking at what
unique capabilities a platform
can provide, and how your app
can benefit from that.
When we looked at the Watch, we
said, well, some of the unique
capabilities of the Watch is
that it can track your movement,
it can track your heartbeat,
your location, and all of that
information is quite relevant
for an app like Activity.
So, if you look at what
additional features we brought
to the Watch, well, you can add
a workout, and you can set move
goals.
And, again, this only makes
sense if you look at the context
and the capabilities of the
Watch.
And that's exactly what adapting
is about.
It is prioritizing your feature,
your features based on the
platform's context and
capabilities, and it's
considering new features that
can benefit from the platform's
unique capabilities.
A really good example of this,
is Photoshop.
For those of you who've used
Photoshop on a MacBook or an
iMac, you know that it's a
really enormous, big app.
There's tons of features in
there.
You can do so many things.
But, Adobe did a really good job
when they tried to bring all
those features to the phone.
They actually broke down the
feature set into 3 really
distinct apps.
All of the interactions are
optimized for quite short
engagements, and they're
embracing the unique
capabilities of a phone by, for
example, being able to take a
picture right from within the
app.
Another good example is the New
York Times.
If you want to read an article
in the New York Times, you can
do that on the phone, on the
iPad, or on their website.
But, if you look at what they've
done on the Watch, you can only
look through a series of the
most recent headlines, and if
you're interested in one of
them, you can flick down and you
can see a small summary of that
article, but if you want to read
the full article, well that's a
longer engagement, so it's no
longer optimized for the Watch.
And, therefore, they ask you to
go to the iPhone, the iPad, or
the website.
So, that was adapting.
In step one, we looked at what
platforms you wanted to go to,
and step two we looked at the
features, and now we're going to
look at the look and feel.
When people talk about look and
feel, they often think about the
word consistent, and that's
definitely a very important word
when we're talking about
bringing your app to multiple
platforms.
But, consistent doesn't mean
identical.
At Apple, we don't just copy and
paste all functionality and all
the visual elements from one
platform to another.
Being consistent is much more of
a balancing act.
You have to balance between two
types of consistency.
On one side, you have your brand
consistency.
This means that when people open
your app, they should recognize
your brand, it should feel very
familiar, and hopefully that
will build trust between the
person who's using your app, and
your brand.
On the other side, you have the
platform guidelines.
This means you'd be using
platform-provided standards, so
your app feels native.
Since these standards reoccur on
all the apps on that platform,
they will feel very
recognizable.
That lowers the cognitive load,
and that eases the learning
curve.
So, finding the balance between
these two types of consistencies
is really important, and maybe
the most difficult exercise in
this whole process.
The human interface guidelines
can be a really good help here.
They can help you understand all
the platform-provided standards
and guidelines, but it can also
help you understand where your
brand can really come alive
within these guidelines.
One example is the typefaces we
have.
You see that for each platform
we have a nice set of typefaces
that you can use, and they're
all optimized for the platform
they're on.
This doesn't mean that you have
to use San Francisco, or you
have to use this specific
typeface or style, but it gives
you a really good idea on what
sizes work well for each
platform.
If you take a look at the body
style for example, on these
three platforms, you'll see that
they nicely scale up, and that
has to do with the viewing
distance.
On a Watch, you look at a Watch
from quite close, maybe a foot
away, so it's quite small.
A phone is a little bit further
maybe one and a half foot, so
it's a tiny bit bigger.
But on a TV as we said before,
it was optimized for a 10-foot
distance, so we made it really
big so you can read it from that
distance quite comfortably.
Apart from the stylistic
features, the human interface
guidelines can also help you
with platform-provided standards
and functionality.
For example, alerts.
Alerts come on every single
platform that we have.
And, they have some common
elements.
They have a description, they
have one or two actions, they
obscure the content behind them.
But, if you look at the length
of the description, the styling
of the buttons, the tap targets,
they're all optimized for each
platform.
So, using an alert like this
will make the -- will be very
familiar to the user,
recognizable, and therefore easy
to use.
The same goes for navigation.
If I want to navigate to the
previous screen on my Watch, I
can just tap the top left
corner.
The same happens on the iPhone.
But, if you look at a TV, well
there is no back button on the
screen.
And, that's because the back
button is actually located on
your remote.
So, there's no need to add an
extra button on the screen to
navigate to, and to click.
So, that's exactly what
conforming is about.
It's finding the balance between
your brand and the platform
guidelines.
It's aligning with your brand,
so your brand feels
recognizable, familiar, and can
create trust.
And, it's aligning with the
platform guidelines and
functionality to lower the
cognitive load and to ease the
learning curve.
A really good example is
Ulysses, and I really hope I'm
pronouncing that right.
If not, I'm sorry.
If you use this app on the iPad,
the iPhone, or the Mac, you'll
notice a whole bunch of
platform-provided standards.
They're using navigation bars,
toolbars, search fields, and
split views.
And, where their brand is really
represented is in the writing
experience.
By allowing dedicated focus, and
quick formatting with markdown,
writing becomes an amazing
experience in this app.
I use this app very frequently
in my process, and in fact, this
presentation started in this
app.
Another good example is Streaks.
With Streaks, you immediately
recognize the brand through the
color, the typography, the
iconography, even the
interaction of long-holding to
complete a task.
But, they really embraced the
platform guidelines with, for
example, doing very smart
notifications, scaling the
typography, and adapting to new
languages.
And a last good example, is
Tinder.
Again, you would recognize the
iconography, you recognize the
colors, the interaction of
swiping left and right.
But, again, they really aligned
with the platform guidelines.
The UI scales up very nicely to
the different platforms, and
their unique interaction of
swiping left and right never
interferes with platform
functionality.
OK, that was step three.
So, if this is the first time
you're going to launch your app
on your first platform, you're
pretty much done.
You selected your platform,
you've defined your features,
you've defined your look and
feel.
Now, you can start building it
and hopefully launch it on the
App Store.
But, if this is an app that you
want to launch on your second,
third, or next platform,
connecting becomes a really
important step.
When we talk about connecting,
two points in your experience
are really important.
You have the entry point and the
exit point.
The entry point is when you open
the app, and you start using it.
The exit point is, hopefully
after a while, when you've done
some work in the app, you close
it and you go do something else.
These two points are really
important, even when you're just
using one platform.
Every time you open the app
again, you hope it doesn't just
give you that same opening
screen.
But, that it actually helps you
create the same environment you
were in the last time you had
the app open.
That is what we call recreating
state.
And, by state, we mean the
content and the information, and
the settings that you were using
the last time you had the app
open.
The state can take any shape or
form depending on what your app
does.
For a simple app like Weather,
for example, it should at least
open up on the same location or
city that you were looking at
the last time you had the app
open.
Preferably with the weather
information updated.
For a more complex app like
Notes, it would open the same
note you were working in last
time, if possible, with the same
tools selected.
And, for apps that revolve
around media for example, like
games, movies, or TV shows, you
would hope it would resume where
you last left off.
So, for example, in the game you
wouldn't have to play that game
all over again just to get to
that same point.
Remembering state becomes even
more important when you're
switching between platforms.
Being able to remember and
recreate the last used state on
any platform creates a very
effortless and delightful
experience.
It allows people to enjoy your
app in whichever context they
like, because you as an app
developer and designer, you will
take care of optimizing that
experience for the platform.
At Apple, we really try to
embrace connecting platforms.
For example, in TV, the state
the TV app remembers is where
you last stopped watching.
The TV show you were watching
and the time you paused is
synced across all the devices,
so you can resume on any
platform of your choosing.
Another good example is Maps.
This morning I looked up on my
MacBook how to get to this
convention center.
Because I did that, that search
went into my recent searches.
And, recent searches is a state
that's being recreated on all
platforms.
So when I step into my car, that
recent search popped up in the
list, I can just tap it and get
going.
This all works really well if
you have your apps set up on all
your platforms, and you're good
to go.
But what happens when a new
platform comes in?
Let's say that you're using a
MacBook and a phone, and
suddenly you buy an iPad, and it
becomes a part of your
day-to-day life.
Well, you install the app on the
iPad, and most of the time
before the app can actually
recreate the state you were in,
it needs a bit more information.
There's an additional step
that's required, which is a
set-up step.
The app needs to know who you
are, so it can recreate the
state you were in, the last time
you had the app open on another
platform.
And, often, such a set-up step
looks something like this.
And, this can be quite
off-putting.
You have to remember your email
address, your user name, your
password, you have to type it
in, you might type it in wrong.
In the end, it might be so
off-putting that you actually
skip this and you don't want to
use this app on your new
platform.
But, luckily with features like
iCloud Keychain, you can just
make this step really effortless
and easy.
With the tap of a button, iCloud
Keychain can fill in your user
name, your email, and your
password, and you're just good
to go.
At Apple, we really embrace this
part as well, this set-up step,
especially with new platforms.
If you buy an Apple TV, you
don't have to set it up
manually, you can just hold your
iPhone or your iPad close to the
Apple TV, and it will move over
all the apps that are compatible
with Apple TV as well as your
iTunes store credentials.
So when the Apple TV has done
setting up, you will recognize
all the apps that are on there,
because you also have them on
your phone, and you can
immediately start buying TV
shows, movies, or games, because
the iTunes store credentials are
there as well.
So, those are really good
examples of connecting.
Connecting is creating a
continuous experience between
platforms, by remembering the
state, and optimizing for the
entry and exit point.
And, it's allowing for a quick
and easy way to use this new
platform.
A really good example is Things.
The state that they're
recreating is your to-do list.
On any platform that you access
Things on, you can add a to-do
item, you can mark one as done,
you can add a due date or
organize it, and it will just
sync that information across all
your devices simultaneously.
Deliveries does a very similar
thing.
It remembers a list of tracking
numbers that you've saved in
iCloud, and it will update the
information from the delivery
service for each single item.
And, that information is
accessible on any platform you
open it up on.
And, a really good example of a
seamless login experience is
Instagram.
If you install Instagram, and
you have Facebook installed, it
will just use those credentials
to get you logged in to
Instagram.
So, with a simple tap of a
button, Instagram is opened up
for you, and you're good to go.
So, that was connecting.
We looked at what happens when
you go from one platform to
another.
In step five, we actually look
at what happens when two
platforms are available at the
same time.
And, to do that, I'm going to go
back to what we talked about in
step one, in selecting, to the
context and the capabilities of
the platforms.
Let's look at the MacBook again.
We said, well, it had a very
high performance, you could do
really precise work with the
keyboard and mouse, it could do
multitasking, but maybe what
it's not really good at, is
exactly knowing who you are.
In fact, when I open up my
MacBook from sleep or I start it
up from when it's off, I get
something like this.
I have to type in my password or
I have to give my Touch ID to
login.
And, again, just like the login
experience before, if I need to
type in my password, that could
be quite off-putting.
I have to remember it, I might
type it wrong, it could take a
couple of times.
But, this is the only way for
the MacBook to know who I am.
There's really no other way for
it to verify my identity.
But, if you bring in a Watch,
well, a Watch is always on and
always with you, and it actually
knows who you are.
So, when these two start talking
to each other, really magical
things can happen.
The Watch can tell you -- can
tell the MacBook, that this is
actually you, and login for you,
and before you know it, your
MacBook just opens up for you.
What's really important to note
here, is how effortless this
experience is.
I don't have to tell my MacBook
to listen to my Watch.
I don't have to tell the Watch
to give information to the
MacBook.
It just happens because they're
close.
In fact, I don't have to do
anything.
So, making an experience
effortless when you have
multiple platforms available, is
really important.
Adding a platform should not
result in adding additional
steps.
Let's look at another platform,
let's look at the iMac.
As we said before, iMac, high
performance, big display, really
good for, for example, browsing
the internet, and maybe even
shopping.
What the iMac cannot do,
unfortunately, is store your
ApplePay card securely.
Which is why you can't do that
on an iMac at the moment.
But an iPhone can.
So when these two start talking
to each other, suddenly payments
are possible.
When you want to buy something
on the iMac, it will tell you to
go to your phone, your phone
will use your securely stored
ApplePay cards, with
authentication with Touch ID,
you confirm the payment, and
you're good to go, the payment
is complete, and you can keep
shopping.
And, this doesn't have to be on
an iPhone, this works on an
iPad, or on a Watch.
What's really important here to
note, is how clear the control
is.
The iMac is clearly telling me
to go to my phone.
On my phone, I get a nice
summary of what I'm going to
purchase.
With Touch ID, I confirm.
The same happens on the Watch
with double click to confirm,
and before I know it, my
purchase is complete, and I can
continue my experience.
So, giving really clear control
is incredibly important when
multiple platforms become
available.
Otherwise, your experience might
become very complicated and
difficult.
And, lastly, let's look at
Keynote.
Keynote is a fantastic app to
make presentations, and also to
give them.
But, one of the downsides of
giving a presentation is that
often, your MacBook is connected
to a display or a projector.
And, so if you want to move
between the slides, you have to
stay behind your MacBook because
the keyboard is the only way to
move between slides.
But when you bring in a phone,
well then, the phone can take
control of what slide is being
shown, and you can freely move
around, because the phone is
light, and easy to carry.
What's important to note about
this experience, is that it's
all optional.
If my phone runs out of battery,
or I forget it, I can still go
back to my MacBook, and use the
keyboard to move between the
slides.
So, making it optional is really
important for multiple devices
in one experience.
So, that's what extending is
about.
We complement different
platforms by combining their
capabilities.
We make clear how to control the
different devices, and we work
toward an optional and
effortless experience.
A really good example is Timber
Tennis.
Games have always really well
understood how multiple
platforms can really create a
magical experience.
This is a great example.
You can play a multiplayer game
with multiple devices if you
have them.
It's completely effortless.
With a simple tap of a button,
you can start a multiplayer
game.
There's very clear control,
because there's only two buttons
on the screen, and it's
completely optional.
You can play with a TV, an
iPhone, or an iPad, or any
combination of that.
And another good example is
Zova.
Zova works really well even if
you only have one device.
If you have an iPad, or an
iPhone, or an Apple TV, you can
start training with Zova, but
the app will always look if
there are more platforms
available in its surroundings.
For example, if you have a
Watch, it will measure your
heartbeat, and that information
is shared amongst all the
devices that you are using.
So, for example, that would
reappear on your TV.
It's a great example of how
effortless this is.
Again, you don't have to do
anything to make this
information being shared across
the devices.
I don't have to tell my Watch to
show my heartbeat on the TV.
And, it's completely optional.
Zova works just as well with one
platform as it does with
multiple platforms.
So, that's the entire process.
We started with selecting our
platform based on the context
and the capabilities of each
platform.
We looked at prioritizing new
and existing features, and
taking advantage of unique
capabilities with adapting.
With conform, we tried to find a
balance between our brand and
the platform guidelines.
In connecting, we looked at what
happens when you go from one
platform to another, and make
that really seamless and
effortless.
And, lastly, we looked at what
magical things can happen when
multiple devices are available
at the same time.
I said in the beginning, we
design our platforms and our
apps to benefit your day-to-day
life, and create a meaningful
relationship.
In the end, we hope that all of
our apps and platforms create a
holistic experience that is
greater than its parts.
With this process we talked
about today, we hope you have
all the tools you need to join
us in that endeavor.
This talk is always available
with this link, and make sure to
check out these sessions too.
There are some really good ones
tomorrow on design as well.
We wish you the best of luck in
bringing your apps to Apple's
ecosystem.
Enjoy the rest of WWDC, and
thank you very much.